const categories = {
    "ESAS MODULE": [

    {
        "question": "A body having identical properties all over it is called",
        "choices": ["Non-homogeneous", "Homogenous", "Isentropic", "Elastic"],
        "answer": "Homogenous"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fatigue failure when a part is subjected to",
        "choices": ["Torsion", "Compressive stress", "Tensile stress", "Flexural stress"],
        "answer": "Compressive stress"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Kepler's Law of motion the square of the time period 'T' of a planet around the sun is proportional to the",
        "choices": ["Cube of the mean distance of planet from sun", "3/2 power of the mean distance", "Mean distance", "Square of the mean distance of planet from sun"],
        "answer": "Cube of the mean distance of planet from sun"
    },
    {
        "question": "A man is standing near the edge of a uniformly rotating platform about an axis passing through its center. The speed of rotation of the platform will decrease if he",
        "choices": ["Moves towards the axis of rotation", "Accepts heavy bag from one man standing nearby and hold it in his hand", "Extends his arms outwards", "Jumps out from the platform"],
        "answer": "Accepts heavy bag from one man standing nearby and hold it in his hand"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a material recovers its original dimensions when the load is removed, it is called",
        "choices": ["Elastic", "Plastic", "Ductile", "Brittle"],
        "answer": "Elastic"
    },
    {
        "question": "The behavior of metals wherein strength of a metal is increased and the ductility is decreased on heating at a relatively low temperature after cold working, is called",
        "choices": ["Clustering", "Twinning", "Strain aging", "Solid hardening"],
        "answer": "Strain aging"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ductile fracture is characterized by",
        "choices": ["Rapid rate for crack propagation", "Negligible deformation", "Fragmentation into more than two pieces", "Appreciable plastic deformation prior to propagation of crack"],
        "answer": "Appreciable plastic deformation prior to propagation of crack"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a complete heat engine cycle, which of the following is the area enclosed by the PV-diagram?",
        "choices": ["The work done by the engine per cycle", "The heat transferred to the engine", "The enthalpy and entropy of the per cycle", "The volume of exhaust gas per cycle"],
        "answer": "The work done by the engine per cycle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following engines is the least efficient?",
        "choices": ["Gas turbine", "Carnot engine", "Diesel engine", "Gasoline engine"],
        "answer": "Gasoline engine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following engines is the most efficient?",
        "choices": ["Gas turbine", "Carnot engine", "Diesel engine", "Gasoline engine"],
        "answer": "Carnot engine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the process that cannot be found in a Carnot engine cycle?",
        "choices": ["Isobaric expansion", "Adiabatic expansion", "Adiabatic compression", "Isothermal expansion"],
        "answer": "Isobaric expansion"
    },
    {
        "question": "In any process, the maximum amount of heat that can be converted into mechanical energy.",
        "choices": ["Depends only on the exhaust temperature", "Depends on the intake and exhaust temperature", "Is always 100%", "Depends on the involvement of kinetic and potential energy involve"],
        "answer": "Depends on the intake and exhaust temperature"
    },
    {
        "question": "The process involved in the transfer of moisture from the sea to the land and back to the sea again is known as",
        "choices": ["Hydrostatic cycle", "Precipitation", "Hydrologic cycle", "Evaporation"],
        "answer": "Hydrologic cycle"
    },
    {
        "question": "A branch of mechanics which deals with the laws governing the behaviors of water and other liquids in the states of rest and motion.",
        "choices": ["Dynamics", "Hydraulics", "Hydrology", "Statics"],
        "answer": "Hydraulics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Formation which contains and transmits groundwater are known as",
        "choices": ["Artesian wells", "Water table", "Diffuse seepage", "Aquifers"],
        "answer": "Aquifers"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flow in which the individual fluid particles follow a straight-line path is known as",
        "choices": ["Laminar flow", "Turbulent flow", "Subcritical flow", "Supercritical flow"],
        "answer": "Laminar flow"
    },
    {
        "question": "A type of flow in which individual fluid particles take a random path.",
        "choices": ["Turbulent flow", "Laminar flow", "Uniform flow", "Non-uniform flow"],
        "answer": "Turbulent flow"
    },
    {
        "question": "When shear force is zero along a section, the bending moment at that section will be",
        "choices": ["Zero", "Maximum", "Minimum", "Minimum or maximum"],
        "answer": "Minimum or maximum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the one that has no unit",
        "choices": ["Kinematic viscosity", "Bulk modulus", "Surface tension", "Strain"],
        "answer": "Strain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hoop stress refers to",
        "choices": ["Circumferential tensile stress", "Radial Stress", "Compressive stress", "Longitudinal Stress"],
        "answer": "Circumferential tensile stress"
    },
    {
        "question": "The intensity of stress that causes unit strain is known as",
        "choices": ["Modulus of rigidity", "Unit stress", "Modulus of elasticity", "Buik modulus"],
        "answer": "Modulus of elasticity"
    },
    {
        "question": "The volumetric change of the fluid caused by a resistance is called",
        "choices": ["Volumetric strain", "Compressibility", "Volumetric index", "Adhesion"],
        "answer": "Adhesion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Modulus of resilience is:",
        "choices": ["the same as the modulus of elasticity", "a measure of a materials ability to store strain energy", "the reciprocal of the modulus of elasticity", "a measure of the strain induced in a member due to a change in temperature"],
        "answer": "a measure of a materials ability to store strain energy"
    },
    {
        "question": "When evaporation takes place within an enclosed space, the partial pressure created by the vapor molecules is called",
        "choices": ["Vapor pressure", "Atmospheric pressure", "Critical pressure", "Absolute pressure"],
        "answer": "Vapor pressure"
    },
    {
        "question": "A graphical representation of stream flow against time is known as",
        "choices": ["Moody Chart", "Hydrograph", "Rainfall chart", "Stream flow chart"],
        "answer": "Hydrograph"
    },
    {
        "question": "The units for dynamic viscosity is",
        "choices": ["N.s/m", "Pa/sec", "Pa.sec", "N.m/s"],
        "answer": "Pa.sec"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cavitation is the result of",
        "choices": ["Improper welding technique", "Exposure of concrete to sea water", "Rivets under impact load", "Static pressure in a fluid becoming less than fluid vapor pressure"],
        "answer": "Static pressure in a fluid becoming less than fluid vapor pressure"
    },
    {
        "question": "A branch of hydraulics which deals with the study of forces (including velocity and acceleration) exerted upon by or upon liquids in motion.",
        "choices": ["Hydrostatic", "Hydrology", "Hydrodynamics", "Hydrokinetics"],
        "answer": "Hydrodynamics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hydraulic radius is given by",
        "choices": ["Area divided by wetted perimeter", "Wetted perimeter divided by area", "Square root of area divided by wetted perimeter", "Area divided by square of the wetted perimeter"],
        "answer": "Area divided by wetted perimeter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a dimensionless parameter?",
        "choices": ["Kinematic viscosity", "Pressure coefficient", "Froude number", "Darcy Weisbach friction factor"],
        "answer": "Kinematic viscosity"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ideal fluid is one that",
        "choices": ["Frictionless and incompressible", "Is very viscous", "Is assumed in problems in conduit flow", "Obeys Newton's Law of viscosity"],
        "answer": "Frictionless and incompressible"
    },
    {
        "question": "The continuity equation is applicable to",
        "choices": ["Conservation of mass", "Viscous and un-viscous fluids", "Steady and unsteady flow", "Compressible fluids"],
        "answer": "Conservation of mass"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pitot tube is a device used for measurement of",
        "choices": ["Flow", "Pressure", "Velocity", "Discharge"],
        "answer": "Velocity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydrometer is used to find out",
        "choices": ["Specific gravity of gases", "Specific gravity of liquids", "Density", "Specific gravity of solids"],
        "answer": "Specific gravity of liquids"
    },
    {
        "question": "The machinability of steel can be increased by",
        "choices": ["Phosphorus, lead and sulfur", "Silicon and sulfur", "Phosphorus and carbon", "Sulfur, graphite and aluminum"],
        "answer": "Phosphorus, lead and sulfur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hastelloy contains",
        "choices": ["Aluminum & nickel", "Nickel & copper", "Nickel & molybdenum", "Copper & molybdenum"],
        "answer": "Nickel & molybdenum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Addition of lead and bismuth to aluminum results in",
        "choices": ["Best known ageing and precipitation", "Improvement of casting characteristics", "Improving machinability", "Improvement of corrosion resistance"],
        "answer": "Improving machinability"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important element that controls the physical properties of steel is",
        "choices": ["Silicon", "Manganese", "Carbon", "Tungsten"],
        "answer": "Carbon"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is the internal resisting moment of a beam, It is opposite in the sense to the bending moment but of the same magnitude.",
        "choices": ["Moment of resistance", "Strain", "Elastic limit", "Modulus of elasticity"],
        "answer": "Moment of resistance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Poisson's ratio is the ratio of the",
        "choices": ["Unit lateral deformation to the unit longitudinal deformation", "Unit stress to unit strain", "Elastic limit to proportional limit", "Shear strain to compressive strain"],
        "answer": "Unit lateral deformation to the unit longitudinal deformation"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a long column (slenderness ratio > 160) which of the following has the greatest influence on its tendency to buckle under a compressive load.",
        "choices": ["The modulus of elasticity of the material", "The radius of gyration of the column", "The compressive strength of the material", "The length of the column"],
        "answer": "The length of the column"
    },
    {
        "question": "The area of the shear diagram of a beam between any two points on the beam is equal to:",
        "choices": ["Change in shear between the two points", "Total shear beyond the two points", "Average moments between the two points", "Change in moment between the two points"],
        "answer": "Change in moment between the two points"
    },
    {
        "question": "Poisson's ratio is principally used in",
        "choices": ["The determination of capability of a material for being shaped", "The determination of capacity of a material for plastic deformation without fracture", "Stress-strain relationships where stresses are applied in more than one direction", "The determination of the endurance limit"],
        "answer": "Stress-strain relationships where stresses are applied in more than one direction"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stress in an elastic material is:",
        "choices": ["Inversely proportional to the material's yield strength", "Inversely proportional to the force acting", "Proportional to the displacement of the material acted upon by the force", "Proportional to the length of the material subject to the force"],
        "answer": "Proportional to the displacement of the material acted upon by the force"
    },
    {
        "question": "A beam, securely fastened to a wall, is subjected to three-dimensional loading. How many components of reaction are possible?",
        "choices": ["Six", "Four", "Nine", "Three"],
        "answer": "Six"
    },
    {
        "question": "The thermodynamic cycle used in a thermal power plant is?",
        "choices": ["Camot", "Ericsson", "Rankine", "Brayton"],
        "answer": "Rankine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Diesel cycle consists of:",
        "choices": ["Isentropic, isothermal, constant volume, constant pressure processes", "Two constant volume, one constant pressure, one isothermal process", "Two isentropic, one constant volume, one constant pressure process", "Two constant pressure, one constant volume, one isentropic process"],
        "answer": "Two isentropic, one constant volume, one constant pressure process"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cycle is generally used for gas turbine?",
        "choices": ["Rankine cycle", "Otto cycle", "Brayton cycle", "Dual cycle"],
        "answer": "Brayton cycle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following provides the basis for measuring thermodynamic property of temperature?",
        "choices": ["Second law of thermodynamics", "Zeroth law of thermodynamics", "Third law of thermodynamics", "First law of thermodynamics"],
        "answer": "Zeroth law of thermodynamics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The triple point of a substance is the temperature and pressure at which",
        "choices": ["The solid and liquid phases are in equilibrium", "The liquid and gaseous are in equilibrium", "The solid, liquid and the gaseous phases are in equilibrium", "The solid does not melt, the liquid does not boil, and the gas does not condense"],
        "answer": "The solid does not melt, the liquid does not boil, and the gas does not condense"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is impossible to construct a heat engine that operates in a cycle and receives a given quantity of heat from a high-temperature body and does equal amount of work. The above statement is known as:",
        "choices": ["Gay Lussac Law", "Kinetic Theory", "Kelvin-Plank Law", "Joule-Thompson Law"],
        "answer": "Kelvin-Plank Law"
    },
    {
        "question": "Brayton cycle has:",
        "choices": ["Two isentropic and two constant volume processes", "Two isentropic and two constant pressure processes", "One constant pressure, one constant volume and two adiabatic processes", "Two isothermal and two constant volume processes"],
        "answer": "Two isentropic and two constant pressure processes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Otto cycle consists of:",
        "choices": ["Two isentropic and two constant volume processes", "Two isentropic and two constant pressure processes", "Two adiabatic and two isothermal processes", "Two isothermal and two constant volume processes"],
        "answer": "Two isentropic and two constant volume processes"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Ericsson cycle has:",
        "choices": ["Two isothermal and two constant pressure processes", "Two isothermal and two constant volume processes", "Two isothermal and two constant entropy processes", "Two adiabatic, one constant volume and one constant pressure process"],
        "answer": "Two isothermal and two constant pressure processes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following engines is the least efficient?",
        "choices": ["Gas turbine", "Carnot engine", "Gasoline engine", "Diesel engine"],
        "answer": "Gasoline engine"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Sterling cycle has:",
        "choices": ["Two adiabatic and two constant volume processes", "Two adiabatic and two constant pressure processes", "Two isothermal and two constant pressure processes", "Two isothermal and two constant volume processes"],
        "answer": "Two isothermal and two constant volume processes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is used for predicting the behavior of non-ideal gases?",
        "choices": ["Compressibility factor", "Expansivity factor", "Emissivity factor", "Van der Waal's factor"],
        "answer": "Compressibility factor"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical point for a mixture occurs for which of the following cases?",
        "choices": ["The vapor and liquid exist in a single form", "The liquid has no absorbed gas", "The vapor phase is stable", "The liquid is completely vaporized"],
        "answer": "The vapor and liquid exist in a single form"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Carnot cycle consists of the following. Which one is NOT?",
        "choices": ["Isentropic compression", "Reversible adiabatic expansion", "Reversible constant heat addition", "Reversible adiabatic compression"],
        "answer": "Reversible constant heat addition"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding organic substances is FALSE?",
        "choices": ["Organic substances generally dissolve in high concentration acids", "All organic matter contains carbon", "Organic matter is generally stable at very high temperature", "Organic substances generally do not dissolve in water"],
        "answer": "Organic matter is generally stable at very high temperature"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the strongest type of bonds?",
        "choices": ["Covalent", "Van de Waals", "Ionic", "Metallic"],
        "answer": "Covalent"
    },
    {
        "question": "An element may be defined as a substance, all atoms of which have the same:",
        "choices": ["atomic weight", "number of neutrons", "atomic number", "radioactivity"],
        "answer": "atomic number"
    },
    {
        "question": "The device which measures the acid content of the cell is called",
        "choices": ["hygrometer", "acid meter", "pyrometer", "hydrometer"],
        "answer": "hydrometer"
    },
    {
        "question": "A deuteron is",
        "choices": ["A neutron plus two protons", "A nucleus containing a neutron and a proton", "An electron with a positive charge", "A helium nucleus"],
        "answer": "A nucleus containing a neutron and a proton"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the same pressure and temperature, equal volumes of all gases contain equal number of molecules. This is known as:",
        "choices": ["Boyle's law", "Faraday's law", "Avogadro's law", "Charles' law"],
        "answer": "Avogadro's law"
    },
    {
        "question": "A substance which gives up protons to another substance is called",
        "choices": ["salt anhydride", "acid", "basic anhydride", "base"],
        "answer": "acid"
    },
    {
        "question": "Elements which generally exhibit multiple oxidation states are",
        "choices": ["Metalloids", "Non-metals", "transition elements", "noble gases"],
        "answer": "transition elements"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Angstrom unit, commonly used for atomic and sub-atomic distances, is:",
        "choices": ["10^-9m", "10^-6m", "10^-10m", "10^10m"],
        "answer": "10^-10m"
    },
    {
        "question": "When two bodies, isolated from other environment, are in thermal equilibrium with a third body, the two are in thermal equilibrium with each other. What do you call this statement?",
        "choices": ["Dalton's law of partial pressure", "First law of thermodynamics", "Zeroth law of thermodynamics", "Second law of thermodynamics"],
        "answer": "Zeroth law of thermodynamics"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is the property of absorbing moisture from atmosphere?",
        "choices": ["Fluidity", "Porosity", "Hygroscopicity", "Insolubility"],
        "answer": "Porosity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross-linking of natural rubber is known as:",
        "choices": ["Raw rubberation", "Vulcanization", "Polymerization", "Sulfurization"],
        "answer": "Vulcanization"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding organic substances is FALSE?",
        "choices": [
            "Organic substances generally dissolve in high concentration acids",
            "All organic matter contains carbon",
            "Organic matter is generally stable at very high temperature",
            "Organic substances generally do not dissolve in water"
        ],
        "answer": "Organic matter is generally stable at very high temperature"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most likely to prove that a substance is inorganic?",
        "choices": [
            "The substance evaporates in room temperature and pressure",
            "The substance is heated together with copper oxide and the resulting gases are found to have no effect on limestone",
            "Analysis shows that the substance contains hydrogen",
            "The substance floats in water"
        ],
        "answer": "The substance is heated together with copper oxide and the resulting gases are found to have no effect on limestone"
    },
    {
        "question": "What element is known as the lightest metal?",
        "choices": ["Magnesium", "Aluminum", "Lithium", "Manganese"],
        "answer": "Lithium"
    },
    {
        "question": "An element may be defined as a substance, all atoms of which have the same:",
        "choices": ["Atomic weight", "Number of neutrons", "Atomic number", "Radioactivity"],
        "answer": "Atomic number"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the measure of the lumen output per watt input produced by the light source?",
        "choices": ["Coefficient of utilization", "Illuminance", "Luminous intensity", "Efficacy"],
        "answer": "Efficacy"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a source of sound is moving with respect to an observer or an observer is moving with respect to the source, what do you call this change in frequency caused by the motion?",
        "choices": ["Skin effect", "Peltier effect", "Doppler effect", "Hall effect"],
        "answer": "Doppler effect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What refers to the computer's use of hard disk storage to simulate RAM?",
        "choices": ["Data storage", "Volatile memory", "Virtual memory", "ROM"],
        "answer": "Virtual memory"
    },
    {
        "question": "What register holds the data being written into or read out of the addressed memory location?",
        "choices": ["Memory data register", "Hold register", "Access register", "Memory address register"],
        "answer": "Memory data register"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special file that is used by the operating system to store the physical location of all the files on a storage medium, such as a hard disk or floppy disk, is called:",
        "choices": ["File format", "Field", "File information table", "File allocation"],
        "answer": "File allocation"
    },
    {
        "question": "A special file that is used by the operating system to store the physical location of all the files on a storage medium, such as a hard disk or floppy disk is called",
        "choices": ["File format", "Field", "File information table", "File allocation"],
        "answer": "File allocation"
    },
    {
        "question": "A megabyte is exactly bytes.",
        "choices": ["1,000,001", "1,000,000", "1,048,576", "999,999"],
        "answer": "1,048,576"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term used to describe the moving of software from another computer to your own computer?",
        "choices": ["Uploading", "Surfing", "Accessing", "Downloading"],
        "answer": "Downloading"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for a high-speed memory used to store a small amount of data temporarily so that the data can be retrieved quickly?",
        "choices": ["Volatile memory", "Cache memory", "Video memory", "Scratchpad memory"],
        "answer": "Scratchpad memory"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of file has a record of website activity?",
        "choices": ["HTTP file", "Cookie file", "Java file", "HTML file"],
        "answer": "Cookie file"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a large computer called?",
        "choices": ["A main frame computer", "A laptop computer", "A mega computer", "A desktop computer"],
        "answer": "A main frame computer"
    },
    {
        "question": "An e-mail address should consist of which of the following?",
        "choices": ["User name and domain name", "User name and user address", "User name and service provider name", "User name, domain name and service provider name"],
        "answer": "User name and domain name"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an input signal A = 10100 is applied to a NOT gate, its output signal will be",
        "choices": ["01011", "00111", "01010", "11011"],
        "answer": "01011"
    },
    {
        "question": "The binary coding scheme most commonly used in microcomputers is called",
        "choices": ["kbps", "bits per second", "ASCII", "hexadecimal"],
        "answer": "ASCII"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mass of a certain object is 10 grams. What would its mass be when taken to the planet Mars?",
        "choices": ["10 grams", "98.1 grams", "10/6 grams", "6 grams"],
        "answer": "10 grams"
    },
    {
        "question": "Are compounds of carbon and hydrogen containing only carbon-carbon single bonds?",
        "choices": ["Alkynes", "Alkanes", "Alkli", "Alkenes"],
        "answer": "Alkanes"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ores from which Titanium is obtained is?",
        "choices": ["Limanite (Ilmenite)", "Bauxite", "Cassiterite", "Sphalerite"],
        "answer": "Limanite (Ilmenite)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call earth and stone mixed with the iron oxide?",
        "choices": ["Gangue", "Hematite", "Diamond", "Magnetite"],
        "answer": "Gangue"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a coal that has been previously burned in an oxygen-poor environment?",
        "choices": ["Diamond", "Tuyere", "Ore", "Coke"],
        "answer": "Coke"
    },
    {
        "question": "are round pieces of flat plastic that store data and program as magnetized spots.",
        "choices": ["CD ROM", "Compact disk", "Hard disk", "floppy disk"],
        "answer": "floppy disk"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does 'TTL' mean?",
        "choices": ["Transmission Time Logic", "Transistorized Transmission Line", "Transistor Logic", "Transformer Tapped Logic"],
        "answer": "Transistor Logic"
    },
    {
        "question": "data is collected over several days or weeks and then processed all at one time.",
        "choices": ["User", "Batch", "Personal", "Master"],
        "answer": "Batch"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does 'CMOS' mean?",
        "choices": ["Complimentary Metal-Oxide Semiconductor", "Computer Metal-Oxide Semiconductor", "Complimentary Main-Oxidation System", "Computer Metal-Oxide Semiconductor"],
        "answer": "Complimentary Metal-Oxide Semiconductor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does 'DTML' mean?",
        "choices": ["Diode Transistorized Maximum Logic", "Diode Transistor Micro Logic", "Diode Transistorized Minimum Logic", "Diode Transistor Macro Logic"],
        "answer": "Diode Transistor Micro Logic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What market situation exists where there are few sellers and few buyers?",
        "choices": ["Bilateral oligopoly", "Oligopoly", "Bilateral oligopsony", "Oligopsony"],
        "answer": "Bilateral oligopoly"
    },
    {
        "question": "The true value of interest rate computed by equations for compound interest for a 1-year period is known as",
        "choices": ["Effective interest", "Expected return", "Economic interest", "Nominal interest"],
        "answer": "Effective interest"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is the present worth of its probable future net earnings.",
        "choices": ["Total fair value", "Going concern value", "Earning value", "Total market value"],
        "answer": "Earning value"
    },
    {
        "question": "When one of the factors of production is fixed in quantity or is difficult to increase, increasing the other factors of production will result in a less than proportional increase in output.",
        "choices": ["Law of demand", "Law of supply", "Law of supply and demand", "Law of diminishing return"],
        "answer": "Law of diminishing return"
    },
    {
        "question": "All the proceeds which are received by the business as a result of the sale of goods.",
        "choices": ["Net revenue", "Net income", "Total sales", "Gross income"],
        "answer": "Gross income"
    },
    {
        "question": "A form of business organization in which a person conducts his business alone and entirely for his own profit, being solely responsible for all its activities and liabilities.",
        "choices": ["Partnership", "Sole proprietorship", "Corporation", "Entrepreneurship"],
        "answer": "Sole proprietorship"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aggregation of individuals formed for the purpose of conducting a business and recognized by a law as a fictitious person is called.",
        "choices": ["Corporation", "Partnership", "Stockholders", "Investors"],
        "answer": "Corporation"
    },
    {
        "question": "The present worth of cost associated with an asset for an infinite period of time is referred as.",
        "choices": ["Capitalized cost", "Annual cost", "Operating cost", "Increment cost"],
        "answer": "Capitalized cost"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unrecovered depreciation results due to poor estimates as to the life of the equipment.",
        "choices": ["In-place value", "Sunk cost", "Annuity", "Economic life"],
        "answer": "Sunk cost"
    },
    {
        "question": "Measure of effectiveness of investment of capital?",
        "choices": ["Rate of return", "Present worth method", "Annual worth method", "Effective interest rate"],
        "answer": "Rate of return"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is otherwise known as 'PRC Modernization Law'?",
        "choices": ["RA 8819", "RA 8981", "RA 7819", "RA 7981"],
        "answer": "RA 8981"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who shall be the executive officer of the Board of Electrical Engineering and shall also conduct the examination given by the Board, as provided in Article II, Sec.9 of R.A. 7920?",
        "choices": ["A member of the Board of EE", "The commissioner of the PRC", "Chairman of the Board of EE", "The president of the Philippines"],
        "answer": "The commissioner of the PRC"
    },
    {
        "question": "From PRC resolution No. 381: Standardized guidelines and procedures for the implementation of CPE (Continuing Professional Education) for all professionals. In Sec.15, the total CPE units for registered professionals with baccalaureate degree shall be credit units for three (3) years.",
        "choices": ["20", "60", "30", "50"],
        "answer": "60"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where installed in two or more raceways, the size of the grounded in each raceway shall be based on the size of the ungrounded service-entrance conductor in raceway but not smaller than m㎡",
        "choices": ["30", "50", "22", "80"],
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground ring encircling the building or structure, in direct contact with the earth, consisting of at least 6,000 mm of bare copper conductor not smaller than mm²",
        "choices": ["30", "38", "50", "22"],
        "answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bonding jumper(s) from grounding electrodes and grounding electrode conductor(s) shall be permitted to be connected to an aluminum or copper busbars not less than",
        "choices": ["6mmx50 mm", "8mmx50mm", "6mmx20 mm", "10mmx50 mm"],
        "answer": "6mmx50 mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum size copper bonding jumper for a service raceway containing 100 m㎡2 THHN aluminum conductors?",
        "choices": ["22m㎡", "50m㎡", "14m㎡", "30m㎡"],
        "answer": "22m㎡"
    },
    {
        "question": "For multi-grounded neutral systems, the maximum distance between any two adjacent electrodes shall not be more than meters",
        "choices": ["350", "100", "400", "125"],
        "answer": "400"
    },
    {
        "question": "Grounding conductors not an integral part of a cable assembly shall not be smaller than copper.",
        "choices": ["50mm²", "22mm²", "30mm²", "14mm²"],
        "answer": "14mm²"
    },
    {
        "question": "What size of conductor shall be connected between the ground grid and all metal parts of swimming pools?",
        "choices": ["14m㎡", "8.0m㎡", "22m㎡", "5.5m㎡"],
        "answer": "8.0m㎡"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where computations result in a fraction of an ampere that is less than such fractions shall be permitted to be dropped.",
        "choices": ["0.51", "0.49", "none of these", "0.50"],
        "answer": "0.50"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground ring encircling the building or structure, in direct contact with the earth, consisting of at least 6,000 mm of bare copper conductor not smaller than m㎡.",
        "choices": ["80", "30", "25", "50"],
        "answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a general rule for the conductors in parallel, aluminum, copper clad aluminum or copper conductors of size _____  m㎡ and larger, comprising each phase, neutral or grounded circuit conductor, shall be permitted to be connected in parallel (electrically joined at both ends to form a single conductor).",
        "choices": ["40", "20", "30", "50"],
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "question": "Minimum height of receptacle above counter top is?",
        "choices": ["500mm", "250mm", "450mm", "300mm"],
        "answer": "500mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "The overall energy program formulated and updated yearly by the DOE and submitted to congress pursuant to R.A. 7638 is known as PEP which means?",
        "choices": ["Philippine Energy Project", "Philippine Energy Plan", "Philippine Electrical Project", "Philippine Electricity Plan"],
        "answer": "Philippine Energy Plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "An electric cooperative, private corporation, government-owned utility, or existing local government unit, that has an exclusive franchise to operate a Distribution System",
        "choices": ["franchise area", "distribution utility", "distribution commission", "generation company"],
        "answer": "distribution utility"
    },
    {
        "question": "The indicative plan for the expansion of power generation and transmission facilities, formulated and updated yearly by the DOE in coordination with Generators, Grid owners, System operators and Distribution utilities.",
        "choices": ["Power development Plan (PDP)", "Philippine Energy Project (PEP)", "Power Expansion Project", "Philippine Power Project"],
        "answer": "Power development Plan (PDP)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two shafts made up of mild steel one having circular cross section and the other being hollow circular with inner diameter half of the outer diameter. The ratio of the torque that can be transmitted in two cases given by",
        "choices": ["1", "2", "15/16", "17/16"],
        "answer": "15/16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is the change in shape of any materials when subjected to the action of a force?",
        "choices": ["Strain", "Moment of inertia", "Stress", "Modulus of elasticity"],
        "answer": "Strain"
    },
    {
        "question": "The twisting moment of a shaft is directly proportional to horsepower and proportional to speed.",
        "choices": ["Inversely, directly", "Inversely, inversely", "Directly, inversely", "Directly, directly"],
        "answer": "Directly, inversely"
    },
    {
        "question": "The property of fluid which determines the amount of its resistance to shearing stress is known as?",
        "choices": ["Reynold's number", "Viscosity", "Surface tension", "Compressibility"],
        "answer": "Viscosity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cyaniding is the process of",
        "choices": ["Dipping steel into cyanide bath", "Reacting steel surface with cyanide salts", "Adding carbon and nitrogen by heat treatment of steel to Increase its surface hardness", "Removing impurities in the cyanide bath"],
        "answer": "Adding carbon and nitrogen by heat treatment of steel to Increase its surface hardness"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the carbon content of pig iron is removed, the almost pure iron remaining is a soft tough metal called",
        "choices": ["Gray iron", "Cast iron", "Wrought iron", "White cast iron"],
        "answer": "Wrought iron"
    },
    {
        "question": "In powder metallurgy, the process of heating the cold pressed metal powder is called",
        "choices": ["Granulation", "Sintering", "Filtration", "Precipitation"],
        "answer": "Sintering"
    },
    {
        "question": "In forgings, what type of carbon steel should be used?",
        "choices": ["Low", "High", "Medium", "Low or Medium"],
        "answer": "Low or Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ratio of stress to strain below the proportional limit?",
        "choices": ["Poisson ratio", "Hooke's constant", "Young's modulus", "Modulus of rigidity"],
        "answer": "Young's modulus"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is a quantity which measures the resistance of the mass to being revolved about the line.",
        "choices": ["Modulus of elasticity", "Stress", "Strain", "Moment of inertia"],
        "answer": "Moment of inertia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a stress-strain diagram, what is the correct term for the stress level at ε=0.2% offset?",
        "choices": ["The elastic limit", "The plastic limit", "The offset rupture stress", "The offset yield stress"],
        "answer": "The offset rupture stress"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does stress concentration occur?",
        "choices": ["I and II", "II and III", "I and III", "I, II, and III"],
        "answer": "I and III"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the value of n (from PV^n = C) for a perfect gas undergoing an isothermal process?",
        "choices": ["0", "Infinity", "1", "n > 1"],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an adiabatic, internally reversible process, what is TRUE about the change in entropy?",
        "choices": ["It is always zero", "It is always greater than zero", "It is always less than zero", "It is infinite"],
        "answer": "It is always zero"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a combustion chamber, fuel is burned to raise the temperature of the medium prior to the production of work through an expansion process. The heat generated during the combustion reaction is the",
        "choices": ["Heat of formation", "Specific heat", "Heat of reaction", "Heat of Vaporization"],
        "answer": "Heat of reaction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most common fluids such as water, oil, gasoline, and alcohol are classified as Newtonian fluid?",
        "choices": ["False", "Charles Law", "True", "Boyle's Law"],
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the heat of a solution is negative, heat is given off when the solute dissolves in the solvent. What type of reaction is this?",
        "choices": ["Endothermic", "Exothermic", "Ideal", "Efflorescent"],
        "answer": "Exothermic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Heating of an ore to bring about its decomposition of a volatile product.",
        "choices": ["Carburizing", "Hot working", "Calcination", "Spheroidizing"],
        "answer": "Calcination"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following group of elements ALL form crystals of the diamond structural lattice?",
        "choices": ["Carbon, Silicon, and Germanium", "Carbon, Boron, and Aluminum", "Lithium, Sodium, and Potassium", "Carbon, Cobalt, and Nickel"],
        "answer": "Carbon, Silicon, and Germanium"
    },
    {
        "question": "The thermodynamics system will produce",
        "choices": ["Large amount of work", "Small amount of work", "Negative work", "Zero work"],
        "answer": "Zero work"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the periodic table of elements, which ONE of the following is a light metal?",
        "choices": ["Gold", "Mercury", "Silver", "Potassium"],
        "answer": "Potassium"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is the attraction between like molecules?",
        "choices": ["Adhesion", "Absorption", "Cohesion", "Diffusion"],
        "answer": "Cohesion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Reactions generally proceed faster at high temperatures because of which of the following?",
        "choices": ["The molecules are less energetic", "The molecules collide more frequently", "The activation energy is less", "The molecules collide more frequently and the activation energy is less"],
        "answer": "The molecules collide more frequently and the activation energy is less"
    },
    {
        "question": "At absolute zero temperature (0 K), all the valence electrons in an intrinsic semiconductor",
        "choices": ["Are in the valence band", "Are in the forbidden gap", "Are in the conduction band", "Are free electrons"],
        "answer": "Are in the valence band"
    },
    {
        "question": "The electrons in an incomplete outer shell are called",
        "choices": ["Valence electrons", "Shell electrons", "Holes", "Chemical electron"],
        "answer": "Valence electrons"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call the probability of finding an electron at any particular point in an atom?",
        "choices": ["Electron capture", "Electronegativity", "Electron density", "Electron affinity"],
        "answer": "Electron density"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a computer system, is a hardware unit where the control keys are located",
        "choices": ["CPUC", "I/O section", "Console", "Keyboard"],
        "answer": "Console"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bus that communicates control and status information is the:",
        "choices": ["Control bus", "Address bus", "Microprocessor", "Data bus"],
        "answer": "Control bus"
    },
    {
        "question": "A boot disk that contains operating system files plus antivirus software is called",
        "choices": ["Reserve disk", "Boot disk", "Restore disk", "Rescue disk"],
        "answer": "Rescue disk"
    },
    {
        "question": "What code is widely used in mainframe computers?",
        "choices": ["Hollerith code", "BCD", "EBCDIC", "Baudot code"],
        "answer": "EBCDIC"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call a device that provides the computer with electricity if there is a power failure?",
        "choices": ["Power supply rectifier", "Uninterruptible power supply (UPS)", "Power inverter", "Automatic transfer switch (ATS)"],
        "answer": "Uninterruptible power supply (UPS)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following devices merges signals?",
        "choices": ["Demodulator", "Oscillator", "Demultiplexer", "Multiplexer"],
        "answer": "Multiplexer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does \"DCTL\" mean?",
        "choices": ["Direct Connected Transistor Logic", "Direct Coupled Transistor Logic", "Diode Coupled Transistor Logic", "Diode Capacitor Transistorized Logic"],
        "answer": "Direct Coupled Transistor Logic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following takes the complete decimal number and represents it in binary?",
        "choices": ["Binary coded decimal", "Straight binary coding", "Excess-3 code", "Gray code"],
        "answer": "Straight binary coding"
    },
    {
        "question": "A source program is a program written in",
        "choices": ["Alphanumeric characters", "Machine language", "ASCII", "High level language"],
        "answer": "High level language"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flow back of profit plus depreciation from a given project is called",
        "choices": ["Capital recovery", "Economic return", "Cash flow", "Earning value"],
        "answer": "Cash flow"
    },
    {
        "question": "The difference between the present and future worth of money at some time in the future.",
        "choices": ["Discount", "Inflation", "Deduction", "Arithmetic progression"],
        "answer": "Discount"
    },
    {
        "question": "The simplest and extensively employed method in computing depreciation",
        "choices": ["Straight line method", "Sinking fund method", "Fixed percentage method", "Sum of integers"],
        "answer": "Straight line method"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the factor formula of the formula?",
        "choices": ["Single payment present worth", "Uniform series sinking fund", "Uniform gradient future worth", "Capital recovery"],
        "answer": "Capital recovery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the other term for \"acid-test ratio\"?",
        "choices": ["Profit margin ratio", "Current ratio", "Price-earnings ratio", "Quick ratio"],
        "answer": "Quick ratio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Form of summary of assets, liabilities and NOT worth",
        "choices": ["Balance method", "Break-even point", "Economics", "Balance sheet"],
        "answer": "Balance sheet"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following clauses is NOT included in Article VI. final provisions of R.A.7920?",
        "choices": ["Separability", "Repealing", "Effectivity", "Penalty"],
        "answer": "Penalty"
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a system permitted to be grounded is a corner-grounded transformer connection.",
        "choices": ["Delta", "Wye", "Delta-wye", "Wye-delta"],
        "answer": "Delta"
    },
    {
        "question": "For service-entrance phase conductors larger than 500 m㎡ copper or 800 m㎡ aluminum, the required grounded conductor for the service shall be sized not less than percent of the area of the largest service-entrance phase conductor.",
        "choices": ["15", "12 ½", "20", "25"],
        "answer": "12 ½"
    },
    {
        "question": "A run of flexible metal conduit may be used as an equipment grounding conductor if the circuit conductor contained in the conduit or protected by overcurrent devices rated at",
        "choices": ["20 Amp or more", "20 Amp or less", "30 Amp or more", "30 Amp or less"],
        "answer": "20 Amp or less"
    },
    {
        "question": "The neutral conductor shall be sufficient ampacity for the load imposed on the conductor but not less than percent of the ampacity of the phase conductors.",
        "choices": ["20", "25", "33", "46"],
        "answer": "33"
    },
    {
        "question": "Connection devices or fittings must not connect grounding conductors to equipment by means of",
        "choices": ["Lugs", "Pressure connections", "Solder", "Approved clamps"],
        "answer": "Solder"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a single-phase, 3-wire AC premises wiring system, which conductor is to be grounded?",
        "choices": ["Ground", "Grounding conductor", "Neutral conductor", "Grounded conductor"],
        "answer": "Neutral conductor"
    },
    {
        "question": "A grounding electrode connection that is encased in concrete or directly buried shall",
        "choices": ["Be minimum 38 m㎡ bare", "Be made accessible", "Be made only by exothermic welding", "Not be required to be accessible"],
        "answer": "Not be required to be accessible"
    },
    {
        "question": "Type USE service entrance cable, identified for underground use in a cable assembly, may have a concentric conductor applied. These constructions shall not require an outer overall covering",
        "choices": ["Bare aluminum", "Bare copper", "Covered metal", "Insulated copper"],
        "answer": "Bare copper"
    }

    ],

"ESAS REFRESHER 1": [

    {
        "question": "What is structural member supported horizontally and carries transverse loading?",
        "choices": ["Column", "Beam", "Arch", "Shaft"],
        "answer": "Beam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a unit of work?",
        "choices": ["N-m", "erg", "dyne", "kg-sq. misq. sec"],
        "answer": "dyne"
    },
    {
        "question": "The three-moment equation may be used to analyze____",
        "choices": ["a continuous beam", "a beam loaded at the third points", "a step tapered column", "an axially end-loaded beam"],
        "answer": "a continuous beam"
    },
    {
        "question": "What refers to the point in which bending moment changes sign through a zero value in strength of materials?",
        "choices": ["Zero stress point", "Critical point", "Point of contra-flexure", "Point of inflection"],
        "answer": "Point of contra-flexure"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the device used to determine the specific gravity of the liquids?",
        "choices": ["Psychrometer", "Hydrometer", "Manometer", "Venturi meter"],
        "answer": "Hydrometer"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what conditions is mass conserved in fluid flow?",
        "choices": ["The fluid is barotropic", "The flow is isentropic", "The fluid is incompressible", "It is always conserved"],
        "answer": "It is always conserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the combination of laminar flow and turbulent flow?",
        "choices": ["Turbulent flow", "Laminar flow", "Critical flow", "Transitional flow"],
        "answer": "Transitional flow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE?",
        "choices": [
            "Steady flow does not change with time at any point.",
            "The Navier-Stokes equation is the equation of motion for a viscous Newtonian",
            "Bernoulli's equation only holds on the same streamline.",
            "The Reynold's number is the ratio of the viscous force to the inertial force."
        ],
        "answer": "The Reynold's number is the ratio of the viscous force to the inertial force."
    },
    {
        "question": "A Kaplan turbine is",
        "choices": [
            "A high head mixed flow turbine",
            "An impulse turbine, inward flow",
            "A reaction turbine, outward flow",
            "Low head axial flow turbine"
        ],
        "answer": "Low head axial flow turbine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What physical property of a material that refers to the point at which a material liquefies or solidifies on cooling?",
        "choices": ["Curie point", "Specific heat", "Melting point", "Refractive Index"],
        "answer": "Melting point"
    },
    {
        "question": "What refers to the measure of the disorder present in a given substance or system?",
        "choices": ["Entropy", "Enthalpy", "Heat capacity", "Molar heat"],
        "answer": "Entropy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following would be identified with control volume in thermodynamics?",
        "choices": [
            "Expansion of gas in a cylinder after combustion",
            "Compression of air in a cylinder",
            "Filling a tire with air at a service station",
            "The Goodyear blimp during flight"
        ],
        "answer": "Filling a tire with air at a service station"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does NOT transfer work to or from a system?",
        "choices": [
            "An electrical resistance heater",
            "A moving piston",
            "The expanding membrane of a balloon",
            "A membrane that burst"
        ],
        "answer": "A membrane that burst"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE for water at a reference temperature when enthalpy is zero?",
        "choices": ["Internal energy is negative", "Entropy is nonzero", "Specific volume is zero", "Vapor pressure is zero"],
        "answer": "Internal energy is negative"
    },
    {
        "question": "A rigid container is heated by the sun. There is NO shaft work associated with the container. From the first law of thermodynamics, what is the resulting work equal to?",
        "choices": ["The change in internal energy", "Zero", "The heat transfers", "The volume times the change in pressure"],
        "answer": "Zero"
    },
    {
        "question": "What would be the most important factor under consideration for the site selection of a thermal plant?",
        "choices": ["Availability of fuel", "Availability of water", "Distance from the populated area.", "Cost and the type of land."],
        "answer": "Availability of water"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the strong bond between hydrogen atoms?",
        "choices": ["The ionic bond", "The metallic bond", "Ionic and metallic bond", "The covalent bond"],
        "answer": "The covalent bond"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a mixed gas such as air, the rms speed of different molecules are",
        "choices": ["proportional to molecular mass", "Independent of molecular mass", "proportional to square root of molecular mass", "inversely proportional to square root of molecular mass"],
        "answer": "inversely proportional to square root of molecular mass"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Van der Waals forces?",
        "choices": ["Primary bonds between atoms", "Forces not present in liquids", "Forces between electrons and protons", "Weak secondary bonds between atoms"],
        "answer": "Weak secondary bonds between atoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of these statements is TRUE for twinning?",
        "choices": ["It is the most significant form of plastic deformation", "It cannot be caused by impact or thermal structure.", "It occurs at lower shear stresses than slip.", "It frequently occurs in hexagonal closed-packed structures."],
        "answer": "It frequently occurs in hexagonal closed-packed structures."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a coal that has been previously burned in an oxygen-poor environment?",
        "choices": ["Tuyere", "Diamond", "Ore", "Coke"],
        "answer": "Coke"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a structural class of steel?",
        "choices": ["Carbon", "Tool and die", "Stainless", "High-strength, low-alloy"],
        "answer": "Tool and die"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross-linking of natural rubber is known as",
        "choices": ["Vulcanization", "Sulfurization", "Raw rubberation", "Polymerization"],
        "answer": "Vulcanization"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following portion of hard disk space served as RAM?",
        "choices": ["Cache", "Random memory", "Read-only memory", "Virtual memory"],
        "answer": "Virtual memory"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is in a machine that it is capable of absorbing and organizing new data, learning new concepts, reasoning logically and responding to inquiries?",
        "choices": ["Self-process intelligence", "Artificial intelligence", "Man-free intelligence", "None of these"],
        "answer": "Artificial intelligence"
    },
    {
        "question": "This MATLAB command clears all data and variables stored in memory:",
        "choices": ["clc", "delete", "deallocate", "clear"],
        "answer": "clear"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does MATLAB stand for?",
        "choices": ["Math Laboratory", "Matrix Laboratory", "MathWorks", "None of these"],
        "answer": "Matrix Laboratory"
    },
    {
        "question": "An instruction that causes data in the accumulator to be moved to the memory or a peripheral register?",
        "choices": ["FETCH", "STORE", "LOAD", "LOOP"],
        "answer": "STORE"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pentium microprocessor has ___ execution units.",
        "choices": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What form of software can also be called firmware?",
        "choices": ["Cache memory", "Operating system", "System BIOS", "Random memory"],
        "answer": "System BIOS"
    },
    {
        "question": "Encryption can provide ALL of the following features of information systems security EXCEPT:",
        "choices": ["Confidentiality", "Integrity", "Authenticity", "Privacy"],
        "answer": "Privacy"
    },
    {
        "question": "HTTP:// is an identifier that appears at the beginning of most web pages. What does HTTP stand for?",
        "choices": ["Hypertime Text Process", "Hypertext Transfer Protocol", "Hypertext Transmission Protocol", "Hypertext Time Process"],
        "answer": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fastest method to transfer data wirelessly is:",
        "choices": ["GPRS", "Infrared", "802.11", "Bluetooth"],
        "answer": "802.11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Characters in MATLAB are represented in their value in memory?",
        "choices": ["Decimal", "ASCII", "Hexadecimal", "String"],
        "answer": "ASCII"
    },
    {
        "question": "In MATLAB, this keyword immediately moves to the next iteration of the loop:",
        "choices": ["Update", "Goto", "Continue", "Break"],
        "answer": "Continue"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the interest occurred over the interest period is also subject to the interest rate in the next period?",
        "choices": ["Quarterly Interest", "Compound Interest", "Simple Interest", "Annual Interest"],
        "answer": "Compound Interest"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following situations has a conventional cash flow so that an internal rate of return can safely be calculated and used?",
        "choices": [
            "You purchase a house and pay the bank in monthly installments",
            "Your company undertakes a mining project in which the land must be reclaimed at the end of the project",
            "You lease a car and pay by the month",
            "You invest in a safe dividend stock and receive a dividend each year"
        ],
        "answer": "You invest in a safe dividend stock and receive a dividend each year"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for ensuring that the project is completed successfully as measured by time, cost, performance, and stakeholder satisfaction?",
        "choices": ["Functional Manager", "Project Manager", "Chief Engineer", "Department Supervisor"],
        "answer": "Project Manager"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a project manager to have an efficient means of identifying and communicating the planned activities and their interrelationships, he must use a network technique. One of the network techniques is commonly known as PERT. What does PERT stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Project Evaluation Review Technique",
            "Program Evaluation Review Technique",
            "Path Evaluation Review Technology",
            "Program Execution Review Technique"
        ],
        "answer": "Program Evaluation Review Technique"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call the ability to convert assets to cash quickly?",
        "choices": ["Leverage", "Insolvency", "Solvency", "Liquidity"],
        "answer": "Liquidity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following corresponds to the meaning of annuity?",
        "choices": [
            "A lumped sum at the end of the year",
            "A series of uniform amounts over a period of time",
            "The future worth of a percent amount",
            "A repayment of a loan"
        ],
        "answer": "A series of uniform amounts over a period of time"
    },
    {
        "question": "Engineers can become good managers through:",
        "choices": ["Experience", "Effective Career Planning", "Taking a Master's Degree", "Trainings"],
        "answer": "Effective Career Planning"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is the process of unifying the power of technology with entrepreneurial skills and capabilities:",
        "choices": ["Entrepreneurship", "Technopreneurship", "Innovations", "Business Management"],
        "answer": "Technopreneurship"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Registered Electrical Engineer (REE) licensure exam, the weight of Engineering Sciences and Allied Subjects (ESAS) is:",
        "choices": ["25%", "30%", "45%", "35%"],
        "answer": "30%"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the present chairman of the board of Electrical Engineering?",
        "choices": ["Hon. Jaime Mendoza", "Hon. Rodolfo Penalosa", "Hon. Francis Mapile", "Hon. Fortunato Leynes"],
        "answer": "Hon. Francis Mapile"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term used when an American citizen is allowed to practice his profession, e.g., electrical engineering profession, here in the Philippines?",
        "choices": ["APEC registry", "ACPE registry", "Foreign Reciprocity", "ASEAN Engr"],
        "answer": "Foreign Reciprocity"
    },
    {
        "question": "In R.A. 7920, IRR rule 2(d) is defining?",
        "choices": ["CPE - Continuing Professional Education", "Board - Board of Electrical Engineering", "Commission - Professional Regulation Commission", "Commissioner - the Chairman of Professional Regulation Commission"],
        "answer": "Board - Board of Electrical Engineering"
    },
    {
        "question": "The clearance between conductors and roof where the service conductors are passing over roofs must be __ mm.",
        "choices": ["1000", "1500", "2000", "2500"],
        "answer": "2500"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where receptacles are connected to a 30-Amp branch circuit, the maximum allowable cord and plug connected load shall NOT be more than _.",
        "choices": ["24", "26", "30", "34"],
        "answer": "24"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a Rigid Metal Conduit (RMC) wiring, conduits shall be supported at least every _ mm.",
        "choices": ["1500", "2000", "3000", "1800"],
        "answer": "3000"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'earth' best defines which of the following terms?",
        "choices": ["bonding", "ground electrode", "ground", "grounded conductor"],
        "answer": "ground"
    },
    {
        "question": "The usual function of a disconnect switch in high voltage circuits is to _.",
        "choices": ["Open the circuit in the event of an overload", "Open or close the circuit under load", "Maintain continuity of service", "Isolate from energized buses, equipment which are not in service"],
        "answer": "Isolate from energized buses, equipment which are not in service"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is 'Murang Kuryente Act'?",
        "choices": ["R.A.11361", "R.A.11285", "R.A.11371", "R.A.10968"],
        "answer": "R.A.11371"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is/are hazardous practice/s?",
        "choices": ["Using equipment improperly", "Failure to warn or secure", "Horseplay", "All of these"],
        "answer": "All of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "Protection of workers from impact penetration from falling and flying objects, blows, and from limited electric shock and burns shall be provided where there is reasonable probability of exposure to such hazards.",
        "choices": ["Hard Hat", "Toe Board", "Harness", "Belt"],
        "answer": "Hard Hat"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under OSHS Rule 1040, a workplace with less than 100 workers is under what type and composition of Health and Safety?",
        "choices": ["Type A", "Type B", "Type C", "Type D"],
        "answer": "Type D"
    },
    {
        "question": "It refers to a portion of the transmission system referring to the lines or wire?",
        "choices": ["Distribution lines", "Sub-transmission lines", "Transmission lines", "Feeder lines"],
        "answer": "Transmission lines"
    },
    {
        "question": "In R.A. 9136, what does PSALM mean?",
        "choices": ["Power System Assets and Liabilities Management Corporation", "Power Sector Assets and Liabilities Management Corporation", "Power System Assets and Liabilities Management Commission", "Power Sector Assets and Liabilities Management Commission"],
        "answer": "Power Sector Assets and Liabilities Management Corporation"
    }


],

    "EE MODULE(1,2,3)": [
    {
        "question": "The resistance of conductor increases",
        "choices": ["when length of conductor increased", "when the resistivity of the wire remains constant", "when the area of the wire is increased", "when length and area of conductor are both increased"],
        "answer": "when length of conductor increased"
    },
    {
        "question": "Factor in determining specific resistance",
        "choices": ["Nature of material", "Area", "Material and length", "Material, area and length"],
        "answer": "Nature of material"
    },
    {
        "question": "Insulation of wire is based on",
        "choices": ["RMS", "Peak", "Average", "1.732 peak"],
        "answer": "Peak"
    },
    {
        "question": "In reverse PN Junction, with the voltage is increasing, the current is",
        "choices": ["increasing", "decreasing", "increasing exponentially", "No change"],
        "answer": "No change"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the heaviest metal?",
        "choices": ["Tungsten", "Cobalt", "Titanium", "Iron"],
        "answer": "Tungsten"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Flemming's Right hand Rule, which finger points the direction of current?",
        "choices": ["Thumb", "Index", "Middle", "Ring"],
        "answer": "Middle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of DC motor is not directly connected to the load?",
        "choices": ["Shunt", "Series", "Universal", "Compound"],
        "answer": "Shunt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a DC motor which one is not considered in determining the speed?",
        "choices": ["Thickness of armature lamination", "Strength of the magnetic field", "Strength in the armature", "Load on the motor"],
        "answer": "Thickness of armature lamination"
    },
    {
        "question": "In dwelling units, at least one wall receptacle outlet shall be installed within ______ mm of the outside edge of basin or bathtub.",
        "choices": ["1200 mm", "1600 mm", "600 mm", "900 mm"],
        "answer": "900 mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "Receptacle outlet shall be located not more than _______ mm above countertop.",
        "choices": ["300", "450", "250", "600"],
        "answer": "450"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sign and outline lighting outlets shall be computed at a minimum of ______ VA for each required branch circuit.",
        "choices": ["1500", "180", "600", "1200"],
        "answer": "1200"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum distance between receptacle outlets in meters of a show window?",
        "choices": ["3", "4", "2", "5"],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "In dwelling units, at least one receptacle outlet for hallways more than ________ m.",
        "choices": ["3", "4", "2", "5"],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Outdoor outlets of one-family dwelling shall be installed not more than _______ mm above grade level at the front or back of the family dwelling.",
        "choices": ["3000", "4000", "2000", "1500"],
        "answer": "2000"
    },
    {
        "question": "Appliance receptacle outlet in dwelling unit for specified appliances shall be installed within _______ mm of the intended location.",
        "choices": ["1,800 mm", "3,700 mm", "1,700 mm", "4,000 mm"],
        "answer": "1,800 mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum ampacity of feeders with motor and other load connected?",
        "choices": ["250% motor FL current plus other current", "125% motor FL current plus other current", "125% total current", "250% total current"],
        "answer": "125% motor FL current plus other current"
    },
    {
        "question": "A fuse is a ________ device?",
        "choices": ["single phase thermal switch", "three phase thermal", "single phase", "three phase protection"],
        "answer": "single phase thermal switch"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the heating process that makes use of the currents induced by the electromagnetic action in the charge to be heated, used for hardening of steel?",
        "choices": ["Dielectric heating", "Convection", "Induction heating", "Infrared heating"],
        "answer": "Induction heating"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Diesel Power plant is best suited as",
        "choices": ["Base Load Plant", "Standby Plant", "Peak Load Plant", "General Purpose Plant"],
        "answer": "Standby Plant"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Philippine Distribution Code Purposes, which of the following does not belong?",
        "choices": ["To ensure quality of electric Power", "To specify Customers services for the protection of end users", "To specify standards for the protection of personnel in the work environment.", "To ensure that distribution system will be operated by only one distribution company."],
        "answer": "To ensure that distribution system will be operated by only one distribution company."
    },
    {
        "question": "In Philippine Distribution Code Power Quality Standards, which of the following does not belong?",
        "choices": [
            "Frequency shall be constant at 60 Hz",
            "THD of the voltage shall not exceed to 5% during normal operating condition",
            "The maximum voltage unbalance at the connection point of any user shall not exceed to 2.5% during normal operating condition",
            "The flicker severity at the connection point of any user shall not exceed to 1.0 unit for short term or 0.8 unit for long term."
        ],
        "answer": "Frequency shall be constant at 60 Hz"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Philippine Distribution Code System Efficiency Standards, power factor at the connection point shall be",
        "choices": ["Not less than 80%", "Not less than 90%", "Not less than 85%", "Always unity"],
        "answer": "Not less than 85%"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Philippine Distribution Code Reliability Standards, the following reliability indices shall be imposed except one",
        "choices": [
            "System Average Interruption Frequency index",
            "System Average Interruption Duration index",
            "Momentary Average Interruption Frequency",
            "Momentary Average Interruption Duration"
        ],
        "answer": "Momentary Average Interruption Duration"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Philippine Distribution Code Safety Standards for Distribution Utilities and Suppliers, the following are adopted except",
        "choices": ["PEC Part 1", "OSHS", "PEC Part 2", "Building Code"],
        "answer": "Building Code"
    },
    {
        "question": "A device used for switching, carrying and interrupting a system for both fault and full load condition.",
        "choices": ["Sectionalizer", "Circuit breaker", "Fuse", "Air break switch"],
        "answer": "Circuit breaker"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of the dielectric is to",
        "choices": ["increase the capacitance", "increase the working voltage", "decrease the capacitance", "reduce the working voltage"],
        "answer": "increase the working voltage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will happen to an insulating medium if subjected to a voltage more than its basic impulse insulation level? It will",
        "choices": ["change its molecular structure", "punctured", "become magnetic", "melt"],
        "answer": "punctured"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Hermetic motor-compressor has 80 A full load current. What is the rating of disconnecting means?",
        "choices": ["92A", "100A", "80A", "200A"],
        "answer": "92A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is not a standard branch circuit rating?",
        "choices": ["30A", "20A", "25A", "40A"],
        "answer": "25A"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum ampacity of conductor to supply a 25 Ampere Electric Heater?",
        "choices": ["31.3 A", "30 A", "35 A", "40 A"],
        "answer": "31.3 A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electric Discharge lamp of 1500A and a 250A incandescent lamp is supplied from a single-phase 3-wire system. What is the neutral current?",
        "choices": ["100 A", "400 A", "385 A", "425 A"],
        "answer": "385 A"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the power factor of a potential transformer?",
        "choices": ["0.97", "0.95", "0.98", "0.99"],
        "answer": "0.99"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is full load efficiency of a power transformer?",
        "choices": ["85%", "90%", "98%", "84%"],
        "answer": "98%"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a DC steady state, a capacitor looks like a/an ________ circuit and an inductor looks like a/an _______ circuit.",
        "choices": ["I and II", "II and III", "III and II", "III and III"],
        "answer": "III and II"
    },
    {
        "question": "What voltage is used to test the insulation resistance?",
        "choices": ["1000 volts", "600 volts", "500 volts", "250 volts"],
        "answer": "500 volts"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the connection of capacitors 1 uF, 3uF & 4 uF needed to have a total of 2 micro-farad.",
        "choices": ["C1 and C2 in parallel, series w/C3", "All in parallel", "C1 & C3 in parallel, series w/ C2", "all in series"],
        "answer": "C1 and C2 in parallel, series w/C3"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a tropical storm is going to the Philippine area of responsibility within 24 hours, what kind of alert is raised according to the Philippine Grid Code?",
        "choices": ["Blue Alert", "Yellow alert", "Weather Disturbance alert", "Red alert"],
        "answer": "Blue Alert"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will happen to the time constant if capacitance is increased?",
        "choices": ["decrease", "increase", "double", "constant"],
        "answer": "increase"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main purpose of a fuse?",
        "choices": ["Protect the line", "Protect the load", "Protect appliances", "limit the excessive current"],
        "answer": "limit the excessive current"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basically, a lightning arrester is a",
        "choices": ["Surge diverter", "Surge reflector", "Surge alternator", "Surge absorber"],
        "answer": "Surge diverter"
    },
    {
        "question": "A switchgear is a device used for",
        "choices": [
            "Interrupting an electrical circuit",
            "Switching an electrical circuit",
            "Switching and controlling an electrical Circuit",
            "Switching, controlling and protecting an electrical Circuit and equipment."
        ],
        "answer": "Switching, controlling and protecting an electrical Circuit and equipment."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the type of communication that only one of the two party can transmit at a time?",
        "choices": ["Full duplex", "Half duplex", "Bicomm", "Simplex"],
        "answer": "Half duplex"
    },
    {
        "question": "Buchholz relay cannot be used on",
        "choices": ["Three phase transformer", "500 KV transformer", "Air cooled transformer", "1000kV transformer"],
        "answer": "Air cooled transformer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Ratio in a transformer",
        "choices": ["Polarization Ratio", "Myers Index", "Neutralization Ratio", "Transformer turn ratio"],
        "answer": "Transformer turn ratio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where a ground fault Circuit Interrupter (GFCI) should be installed? (I. Garage II. Bathroom III. Outside IV. Dining Room V. Guest Room)",
        "choices": ["I, II, III", "I, IV, V", "I, II, V", "I, III, IV"],
        "answer": "I, II, III"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the type of relay that detect excessive current?",
        "choices": ["Differential Relay", "Reverse current Relay", "Overcurrent Relay", "Overvoltage Relay"],
        "answer": "Overcurrent Relay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum size grounding electrode copper conductor?",
        "choices": ["3.5 sq.mm", "8.0 sq.mm", "5.5 sq.mm", "14 sq.mm"],
        "answer": "8.0 sq.mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum size grounding rod?",
        "choices": ["10mm", "12mm", "13mm", "16mm"],
        "answer": "16mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum size of wire in lighting outlet?",
        "choices": ["2.0 sq.mm.", "5.5 sq.mm.", "3.5 sq.mm.", "1.6 sq.mm."],
        "answer": "2.0 sq.mm."
    },
    {
        "question": "The lighting load for an office expressed in terms of volt-ampere per square meter must be at least",
        "choices": ["16 VA/sq.m", "28 VA/sq.m", "12 VA/sq.m", "24 VA/sq.m"],
        "answer": "28 VA/sq.m"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an electron moves because of the pressure applied to it. What is the resulting process?",
        "choices": ["flow of current", "melting", "magnetic induction", "generating"],
        "answer": "flow of current"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of luminaire is permitted in clothes closet?",
        "choices": [
            "surface mounted or recessed fixture with complete enclosed lamp",
            "pendant luminaire",
            "incandescent fixture with partially enclosed lamp",
            "incandescent fixture with open lamp"
        ],
        "answer": "surface mounted or recessed fixture with complete enclosed lamp"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fermi energy is the amount of energy which",
        "choices": [
            "a hole can have at room temperature",
            "a valence electron can have at room temperature",
            "must be given to an electron to move it to conduction band",
            "must be given to hole to move it in valence band"
        ],
        "answer": "must be given to an electron to move it to conduction band"
    },
    {
        "question": "The interrupting capacity of circuit breaker is generally determined by ______.",
        "choices": ["symmetrical fault", "line to ground fault", "asymmetrical fault", "line to line fault"],
        "answer": "symmetrical fault"
    },
    {
        "question": "In dwelling unit, floor receptacle/outlets shall not be counted as part of the required receptacle outlets unless located within ______ mm of the wall.",
        "choices": ["1800", "1600", "450", "600"],
        "answer": "450"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum surface area exposed for plate electrode?",
        "choices": ["1/6 m²", "1/4 m²", "1/5 m²", "1/3 m²"],
        "answer": "1/5 m²"
    },
    {
        "question": "Receptacle shall be installed so that no point along the floor line in any wall space is more than ________ mm, measured horizontally, from an outlet in that space.",
        "choices": ["1800", "1200", "1500", "1000"],
        "answer": "1800"
    },
    {
        "question": "In metering, kwhr meter in conjunction with varhr-meter is used to determine ______.",
        "choices": ["Load Factor", "Use Factor", "Power Factor", "Demand Factor"],
        "answer": "Power Factor"
    },
    {
        "question": "An electromagnetic device for finding the short circuit",
        "choices": ["Hi-pot", "Ohm-meter", "Growler", "Megger"],
        "answer": "Growler"
    },
    {
        "question": "A device that recloses a circuit or isolates a faulted line.",
        "choices": ["Circuit breaker", "Sectionalizer", "Recloser", "Disconnect Switch"],
        "answer": "Recloser"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the time at which the load is disconnected when there is fault.",
        "choices": ["Arcing time", "Melting time", "Cut-off time", "Operating time"],
        "answer": "Operating time"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum output of cellular transmitter?",
        "choices": ["3 W", "30 W", "6 W", "60 W"],
        "answer": "3 W"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency variation of FM transmitter is expressed as a function of _______.",
        "choices": ["AM", "FM", "Amplitude", "Phase"],
        "answer": "Phase"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does not belong for grid design?",
        "choices": ["Capacity", "Timing", "Voltage", "Circuit Design"],
        "answer": "Timing"
    },
    {
        "question": "In grounding, which is permitted as grounding electrode? (I. Building Metal Frame II. Metal Water pipe)",
        "choices": ["I only", "II only", "both I & II", "neither I nor II"],
        "answer": "both I & II"
    },
    {
        "question": "A circuit must be protected against",
        "choices": ["overload", "short circuit", "overload, short circuit, earth leakage, voltage spikes", "earth leakage"],
        "answer": "overload, short circuit, earth leakage, voltage spikes"
    },
    {
        "question": "The location of the disconnecting means from the second building",
        "choices": ["I only", "II only", "both I & II", "neither I nor II"],
        "answer": "both I & II"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the modern light sensor used in fax machine?",
        "choices": ["Phototransistor", "Phototube", "Liquid Crystal Display (LCD)", "Charged Coupled Device"],
        "answer": "Charged Coupled Device"
    },
    {
        "question": "In single phase, 3-wire system, the middle conductor must be which of the following",
        "choices": ["hot wire", "ungrounded wire", "grounded wire", "out-of-phase wire"],
        "answer": "grounded wire"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many three-way and four-way switches are needed for a lighting system controlled in five different locations?",
        "choices": ["2-3Way & 3-4Way", "1-3Way & 4-4Way", "3-3Way & 2-4Way", "4-3Way & 1-4Way"],
        "answer": "2-3Way & 3-4Way"
    },
    {
        "question": "_______ is also known as 'Cold Standby Reserve'",
        "choices": ["Back-up reserve", "Spinning reserve", "Contingency reserve", "Power reserve"],
        "answer": "Back-up reserve"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is included in the calculation of reliability indices of Distribution Code?",
        "choices": ["Outages in the Generation", "500 kV line outages", "34.5 kV line outages", "230 kV line outages"],
        "answer": "34.5 kV line outages"
    },
    {
        "question": "One farad is",
        "choices": ["coulomb-joule", "joule per volt", "one coulomb per volt", "one volt per coulomb"],
        "answer": "one coulomb per volt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The permeability of the material means",
        "choices": ["Strength of permanent magnet", "Strength of an electromagnet", "The conductivity of the material for magnetic lines of force", "The magnetization left in the iron after exciting field has been removed"],
        "answer": "The conductivity of the material for magnetic lines of force"
    },
    {
        "question": "Induction motor is running at rated load. What will happen when one winding of a delta connected motor is suddenly cut?",
        "choices": ["run fast", "stop", "run slow", "will burn"],
        "answer": "will burn"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of the current is only made known by the effect it produces. Three important effects are:",
        "choices": ["Heating, electric shock and generation", "heating, magnetic and electric shock", "generation, chemical and electric shock", "heating, magnetic and chemical"],
        "answer": "heating, magnetic and electric shock"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the suitable connection to be used in unbalanced three-phase?",
        "choices": ["3 phase, 3 wire Y-connection", "3 phase, 4 wire Y-connection", "Delta connection", "Open delta connection"],
        "answer": "3 phase, 4 wire Y-connection"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a vector quantity?",
        "choices": ["Magnetic potentials", "Magnetic field density", "Flux density", "Relative permeability"],
        "answer": "Magnetic field density"
    },
    {
        "question": "The torque of a synchronous motor when it reaches its synchronism is called",
        "choices": ["Pull-in torque", "Break away Torque", "Pull-out torque", "Running Torque"],
        "answer": "Pull-in torque"
    },
    {
        "question": "The law that induces emf and current always opposes the cause producing them was discovered by",
        "choices": ["Lenz", "Maxwell", "Faraday", "Ohm"],
        "answer": "Lenz"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the left-hand rule, the thumb always represents",
        "choices": ["Voltage", "Direction of force on conductor", "Current", "Magnetic field"],
        "answer": "Direction of force on conductor"
    },
    {
        "question": "If P = number of pair of poles, f = the frequency in Hz, N = speed in rpm, the relationship between the three for synchronous alternators is given as",
        "choices": ["f=PN/120 Hz", "P=fN/120 poles", "f=PN/60 Hz", "N=fP/120 rpm"],
        "answer": "f=PN/120 Hz"
    },
    {
        "question": "In wye system, the phase current is _______ (of) line current.",
        "choices": ["less than", "equal to", "1.732", "0.577"],
        "answer": "equal to"
    },
    {
        "question": "The magnetism that remains in a magnet after magnetizing force has been removed is called",
        "choices": ["Permeability", "Residual", "Induction", "Saturation"],
        "answer": "Residual"
    },
    {
        "question": "A wattmeter is installed in a balanced 3-phase system with current coil at line A while voltage coil across B and C. The wattmeter will measure",
        "choices": ["total power", "active power", "real power", "reactive power"],
        "answer": "reactive power"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following heating methods is based on the transformer principle?",
        "choices": ["Resistance heating", "Induction heating", "Eddy current heating", "Dielectric heating"],
        "answer": "Induction heating"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the IEEE standard device number for distance relay?",
        "choices": ["51", "52", "21", "87"],
        "answer": "21"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the device number for differential protective relay?",
        "choices": ["89", "87", "64", "81"],
        "answer": "87"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuse on the motor is used to (I. Short circuit Protection II. Overload Protection)",
        "choices": ["I only", "II only", "Both I & II", "Either I or II"],
        "answer": "I only"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characteristic of fuse does not need in choosing a fuse?",
        "choices": ["Voltage rating", "Contact Resistance", "Interrupting capacity", "Breaking capacity"],
        "answer": "Contact Resistance"
    },
    {
        "question": "General lighting load for store shall be calculated as _______ VA per sqm.",
        "choices": ["16", "8", "28", "24"],
        "answer": "24"
    },
    {
        "question": "Minimum thickness of concrete in a concrete encased electrode is",
        "choices": ["50mm", "70mm", "60mm", "80mm"],
        "answer": "50mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Electrode is not permitted for grounding?",
        "choices": ["Aluminum electrode", "Metal frame of the building structure", "Concrete encased electrode", "Metal underground water pipes"],
        "answer": "Aluminum electrode"
    },
    {
        "question": "A permanent joining of metal parts to form an electrically conductive path that ensures electrical continuity and the capacity to conduct safety any current likely to be imposed.",
        "choices": ["Counterpoise", "Air Terminal", "Interlink", "Bonding"],
        "answer": "Bonding"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ground ring shall be buried at a depth below the earth's surface not less than _______ mm.",
        "choices": ["500mm", "1000mm", "750mm", "600mm"],
        "answer": "750mm"
    },
    {
        "question": "The color used to indicate grounding conductor larger than 14 sqmm are ______, ______ and _______. (I. Yellow, II. White, III. Gray, IV. Any color with three white stripe except green.)",
        "choices": ["I, II, III", "II, III, IV", "I, II, IV", "I, II, III, IV"],
        "answer": "II, III, IV"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum length and size of grounding electrode conductor.",
        "choices": ["5000mm, 22sqmm", "5000mm, 30 sqmm", "6000mm, 22 sqmm", "6000mm, 30 sqmm"],
        "answer": "6000mm, 22 sqmm"
    },
    {
        "question": "Month of March is the fire prevention month, what is the Electrical Safety month?",
        "choices": ["February", "May", "April", "June"],
        "answer": "May"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Epira Law, where does 1,000 volts - 34,500 volts belong?",
        "choices": ["high voltage", "Extra high voltage", "low voltage", "Medium voltage"],
        "answer": "Medium voltage"
    },
    {
        "question": "In EPIRA Law, the term WESM means?",
        "choices": ["Whole Sale Electricity Spot Market", "Whole Sale Energy Spot Market", "Waste Energy Spot Market", "World Electrical Mechanical System"],
        "answer": "Whole Sale Electricity Spot Market"
    },
    {
        "question": "Scope of RME is up to how much kVA at 600 volts?",
        "choices": ["300", "100", "500", "250"],
        "answer": "500"
    },
    {
        "question": "Construction of service entrance cap must be _________.",
        "choices": ["weatherproof", "Raintight", "watertight", "Rain proof"],
        "answer": "Raintight"
    },
    {
        "question": "All line wires shall be protected by an approved electrical conduit including ______ conductor.",
        "choices": ["Grounding", "Bonding", "Bonded", "Grounded"],
        "answer": "Grounding"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ohmmeter reading for a shorted capacitor is",
        "choices": ["Infinity", "Few mega ohms", "Few kilos ohm", "Zero"],
        "answer": "Zero"
    }
	    
],

    "ESAS REFRESHER 3": [
      {
        "question": "If the mass on a body were doubled, its acceleration due to gravity would be",
        "choices": ["doubled", "haived", "unchanged", "four times"],
        "answer": "unchanged"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following anchor is designed for medium and heavy weight fastening in solid materials?",
        "choices": ["Anchor clamp", "Toggle bolt anchor", "wall grip anchor", "stud-bolt anchor"],
        "answer": "stud-bolt anchor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which type of loading does fatigue occur?",
        "choices": ["Static load", "Plane load", "Repeated load", "Higher load"],
        "answer": "Repeated load"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of the moment of inertia of the cross-section of the beam to the section modulus.",
        "choices": ["Equal to the radius gyration", "Equal to the area of the cross-section", "Measure a distance", "Dependent on the modulus of elasticity of the beam measure"],
        "answer": "Measure a distance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unit of Strain is",
        "choices": ["meter", "milimeter", "MPa", "unitless"],
        "answer": "unitless"
    },
    {
        "question": "Poisson's ratio is the ratio of the",
        "choices": [
            "Unit lateral deformation to the unit longitudinal deformation",
            "Unit stress to unit strain",
            "Elastic limit to proportional limit",
            "Shear strain to compressive strain"
        ],
        "answer": "Unit lateral deformation to the unit longitudinal deformation"
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple beam 'L' meters long carries a concentrated load of 'P' Newtons at the midspan. What is the maximum bending moment of the beam?",
        "choices": ["PL/4", "PL2/4", "PL/2", "PL2/6"],
        "answer": "PL/2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are NOT units of pressure?",
        "choices": ["Pa", "N/m²", "bars", "kg/m²"],
        "answer": "kg/m²"
    },
    {
        "question": "Device used to measure the velocity of a liquid?",
        "choices": ["Venturi meter", "Manometer", "Bourdon gauge", "Pitot tube"],
        "answer": "Pitot tube"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following valves are used for shut-off service. Which one is NOT included?",
        "choices": ["plug cock", "ball valve", "butterfly valve", "gate valve"],
        "answer": "butterfly valve"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which of the following conditions is Bernoulli's equation valid?",
        "choices": [
            "All points evaluated must be on the same streamline",
            "The fluid must be incompressible",
            "The fluid must be inviscid",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point at which solid, liquid and vapor forms of a substance simultaneously exist.",
        "choices": ["Critical", "Boiling", "Triple", "Flash"],
        "answer": "Triple"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does an adiabatic process compare to an isentropic process?",
        "choices": [
            "adiabatic: heat transfer = 0; isentropic: heat transfer ≠ 0",
            "adiabatic: heat transfer ≠ 0; isentropic: heat transfer = 0",
            "adiabatic: reversible; isentropic: not reversible",
            "both: heat transfer = 0; isentropic: reversible"
        ],
        "answer": "both: heat transfer = 0; isentropic: reversible"
    },
    {
        "question": "An open system of First Law of Thermodynamics should be utilized for all the following, EXCEPT",
        "choices": ["A turbine", "A compressor", "A piston-cylinder device with no inlet/outlet", "A nozzle"],
        "answer": "A piston-cylinder device with no inlet/outlet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What law of nature underpins the concept of balanced chemical equation?",
        "choices": ["Gay-Lussac Law", "Faraday's Law", "Second law of thermodynamics", "First law of Thermodynamics"],
        "answer": "First law of Thermodynamics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following thermodynamic cycles is the most efficient?",
        "choices": ["Brayton", "Rankine", "Carnot", "Combined Brayton-Rankine"],
        "answer": "Carnot"
    },
    {
        "question": "What cycle is used for cooling system for aircraft?",
        "choices": ["Bell-Coleman", "Carnot", "Brayton", "Reverse Brayton"],
        "answer": "Bell-Coleman"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the charge of elements that belongs to group 2A (IIA)?",
        "choices": ["+1", "-1", "+2", "-2"],
        "answer": "+2"
    },
    {
        "question": "In electrolysis, the anions migrate to the anode. Which of the following ions migrate to the other electrode?",
        "choices": ["Acidic ions", "Neutral ions", "Basic ions", "Cations"],
        "answer": "Cations"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Calcium Chloride?",
        "choices": ["CaCl3", "CaCl2", "Ca2Cl", "Ca3Cl"],
        "answer": "CaCl2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What per cent of human body is carbon?",
        "choices": ["24%", "18%", "15%", "20%"],
        "answer": "18%"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the percent of alcohol in a 90-proof whisky?",
        "choices": ["40%", "45%", "90%", "10%"],
        "answer": "45%"
    },
    {
        "question": "What field of study encompasses the procurement and production of metals?",
        "choices": ["Metallurgy", "Geology", "Material Science", "Metalgraphy"],
        "answer": "Metallurgy"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many atoms are in the unit cell of a body-centered cubic (BCC) structure?",
        "choices": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the generic name of a class of polymer which is commercially known as nylon?",
        "choices": ["Polyacetals", "Polyamide", "Cellulose", "Polyester"],
        "answer": "Polyamide"
    },
    {
        "question": "For completely corrosion-resistant stainless steel, what minimum percentage of chromium in the alloy is required?",
        "choices": ["1.1%", "3.2%", "15%", "11%"],
        "answer": "11%"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following materials is NOT a viscoelastic material?",
        "choices": ["plastic", "metals", "concrete", "glass"],
        "answer": "metals"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of materials usually has a higher index of refraction?",
        "choices": ["Lighter materials", "Heavier materials", "less dense materials", "denser materials"],
        "answer": "denser materials"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following bus has a function of directing memory and I/O devices transfer?",
        "choices": ["Data", "Device", "Address", "Control"],
        "answer": "Control"
    },
    {
        "question": "On systems where there are multiple operating systems, the decision to load a particular one is done by?",
        "choices": ["File control block", "Process control block", "boot loader", "bootstrap"],
        "answer": "boot loader"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the standardized communication technique for expressing instructions to a computer?",
        "choices": ["flow chart", "programming language", "algorithm", "logic"],
        "answer": "programming language"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is an act of sending e-mail or creating web pages that are designed to collect an individual's online bank, credit card or other login information?",
        "choices": ["Phishing", "Spam", "Hacking", "Malware"],
        "answer": "Phishing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call a person who gains illegal access to a computer system?",
        "choices": ["Computer enthusiasts", "Electronic enthusiasts", "Hacker", "Computer pirate"],
        "answer": "Hacker"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following computer program is NOT considered open-source software?",
        "choices": ["Firefox", "Microsoft office", "Linux", "OpenOffice.org"],
        "answer": "Microsoft office"
    },
    {
        "question": "A technician has installed a new video card and the computer will now only boot into VGA mode. Which of the following may be the cause of the problem?",
        "choices": ["There is an operating system incompatibility.", "The external monitor is not compatible", "The new card is not DVI compatible", "The incorrect drivers are installed"],
        "answer": "The incorrect drivers are installed"
    },
    {
        "question": "When installing the heatsink back into a computer after replacing a failed processor, which of the following must be done during installation?",
        "choices": ["Thermal compound must be installed between processor and heatsink.", "Thermal compound must be installed between processor and system board", "An isopropyl alcohol pad must be placed between the processor and the heatsink", "An isopropyl alcohol pad must be placed between the processor and the system board."],
        "answer": "Thermal compound must be installed between processor and heatsink."
    },
    {
        "question": "Matthew is downloading an 800 kB file from the internet using his 28.8 k modem. How long will it take him to finish downloading?",
        "choices": ["0.46 min", "3.7 min", "3.8 min", "4.1 min"],
        "answer": "3.8 min"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a spreadsheet, the formula $A$3+$B3+D2 is entered into cell C2. The contents of cell C2 are copied and pasted into cell D5. The formula in cell D5 is?",
        "choices": ["$A$3+CS2+C4", "$B$6+SC4+C4", "$A$3+$B6+E5", "$A$3+$B2+B2"],
        "answer": "$A$3+$B6+E5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which function is NOT provided by the MATLAB Mathematical function library?",
        "choices": ["Bessel functions", "Matrix eigenvalues", "Fourier transforms", "Line diagram"],
        "answer": "Line diagram"
    },
    {
        "question": "The MATLAB command will correctly define x, y, and z as symbols?",
        "choices": ["syms (x,y,z)", "syms xyz", "sym (x, y,z)", "sym x,y,z"],
        "answer": "syms xyz"
    },
{
        "question": "MATLAB command for getting the roots of 3x^2-4x+7=0",
        "choices": ["Roots", "Poly", "Polyfit", "Plot"],
        "answer": "Roots"
    },
    {
        "question": "By default, all the files in C++ are opened in ___ mode.",
        "choices": ["Binary", "VTC", "ISCII", "Text"],
        "answer": "Text"
    },
    {
        "question": "In financial accounting another term for Acid Test Ratio is",
        "choices": ["Quick ratio", "Current ratio", "Profit margin ratio", "Price-earning ratio"],
        "answer": "Quick ratio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Future worth is equivalent to _",
        "choices": ["P(1+n)Nj", "Pi1+nj^(n-1)", "P(1+i)^n", "Pi1+i)^(-n)"],
        "answer": "P(1+i)^n"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following expressions is INCORRECT?",
        "choices": [
            "The future worth of a present amount, (F/P, i, n)= 1/(P/F, i,n)",
            "The future worth of an annuity, (F/A,i, n)= 1/(AAF,i, n)",
            "The present worth of an annuity,(P/A,i n) = iA/P, i, n)",
            "(ArF i, n)-i=(AP,i, n)"
        ],
        "answer": "(ArF i, n)-i=(AP,i, n)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of property in which a willing buyer will pay to a willing seller for a property when neither one is under the compulsion to buy nor sell is called _ value.",
        "choices": ["Goodwill", "Second-hand", "Market", "Fair"],
        "answer": "Market"
    },
    {
        "question": "What refers to the establishing interrelationships between people and things in such a way that human and material resources are effectively focused toward achieving the goal of the company?",
        "choices": ["Planning", "Leading", "Organizing", "Controlling"],
        "answer": "Organizing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following techniques must a manager use if he decides to absorb the risk in the project?",
        "choices": [
            "Use a different technology",
            "Buying insurance",
            "Use a different supplier",
            "Create buffer in the form of management reserve or extra time to schedule"
        ],
        "answer": "Create buffer in the form of management reserve or extra time to schedule"
    },
    {
        "question": "A bank is advertising 9.5% account that yield 9.84% annually. Find how often interest is compounded.",
        "choices": ["Monthly", "Bimonthly", "Annually", "Quarterly"],
        "answer": "Quarterly"
    },
    {
        "question": "When was R.A. 7920 passed by the House of Representatives and the Senate?",
        "choices": ["February 14, 1995", "February 21, 1994", "February 24, 1995", "February 21, 1995"],
        "answer": "February 21, 1995"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a requirement for PRBEE?",
        "choices": [
            "At least 40 yrs old, good moral conduct",
            "At least 10 yrs experience",
            "Resident of the PH for 5 consecutive years",
            "Graduated BSEE from a PH-gov't recognized institution"
        ],
        "answer": "At least 40 yrs old, good moral conduct"
    },
    {
        "question": "Based on section 18 of R.A. 7920, the minimum age requirement for qualifications of applicants for Registered Master Electrician (RME) examination is at least _ years of age.",
        "choices": ["18", "19", "21", "23"],
        "answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Rule 11 in R.A. 7920?",
        "choices": ["Action on Communication", "Places and Dates of Examinations", "Program of Examination", "Publication of Examination"],
        "answer": "Places and Dates of Examinations"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is qualified as the chairman of the Continuing Professional Development Council for Electrical Engineering?",
        "choices": [
            "Representative from Association of Professional Organization (APO)",
            "PRBEE board member",
            "Representative from Academy",
            "PRC Commissioner"
        ],
        "answer": "PRBEE board member"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrical equipment must be grounded to ensure that dangerous voltage on metal parts resulting from a ground fault can be reduced to a safe value. (I. True, II. False)",
        "choices": ["I only", "II only", "Both I or II", "Either I or II"],
        "answer": "I only"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rod and pipe electrodes shall NOT be less than ___ mm in length.",
        "choices": ["1,500", "2,400", "1,800", "2,800"],
        "answer": "2,400"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following insulation color identifies the grounded conductor of a branch circuit?",
        "choices": ["Black", "Yellow", "Green", "White"],
        "answer": "White"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a hazardous practice?",
        "choices": [
            "Using the right tools/equipment",
            "Using improvised tools",
            "Servicing equipment in motion",
            "Operating without authority"
        ],
        "answer": "Using the right tools/equipment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the standard color for safety signages to indicate the presence of radiation hazards, example in the X-ray laboratory in the hospital?",
        "choices": ["Green with combination of red", "Orange", "Blue", "Purple with combination of yellow"],
        "answer": "Purple with combination of yellow"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Law for renewable energy?",
        "choices": ["R.A. 9136", "R.A. 11285", "R.A. 11361", "R.A. 9513"],
        "answer": "R.A. 9513"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tall growing plants refer to plants, vines, and other plant species, which grow or have the potential to grow more than _ in height from the ground.",
        "choices": ["2 meters", "5 meters", "1 meter", "3 meters"],
        "answer": "3 meters"
    },
    {
        "question": "The land beneath, the air spaces surrounding, and the area traversed by power lines including its horizontal, vertical, and similar clearance requirements shall constitute the ___",
        "choices": ["Creepage distance", "Private property", "Power line corridor", "Public property"],
        "answer": "Power line corridor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Law for Anti-Obstruction of powerline?",
        "choices": ["R.A. 9136", "R.A. 11285", "R.A. 11361", "R.A. 9513"],
        "answer": "R.A. 11361"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Law for Energy Eff and Covservation Act?",
        "choices": ["R.A. 9136", "R.A. 11285", "R.A. 11361", "R.A. 9513"],
        "answer": "R.A. 11285"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Epira Law?",
        "choices": ["R.A. 9136", "R.A. 11285", "R.A. 11361", "R.A. 9513"],
        "answer": "R.A. 9136"
    }

],

    "EE PREBOARDS": [
        {
            "question": "What is the best conductor of electricity?",
            "choices": ["Polyethylene", "Ceramic", "China Clay", "Graphite"],
            "answer": "Graphite"
        },
        {
            "question": "You wish to triple the rate of energy dissipation in a heating device. To do this you could triple",
            "choices": [
                "the potential difference keeping the resistance the same",
                "the current keeping the resistance the same",
                "the resistance keeping the potential the same",
                "the resistance keeping the current the same"
            ],
            "answer": "the resistance keeping the current the same"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a series circuit the current is",
            "choices": ["constant", "variable", "proportional to the resistance", "inversely proportional to the resistance"],
            "answer": "constant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Regarding Thevenin's equivalent, which of the following is not correct?",
            "choices": [
                "The voltage source in the Thevenin equivalent circuit is open circuit voltage of the network",
                "The Thevenin equivalent resistance is the resistance of the network when all voltage sources",
                "The Thevenin equivalent resistance is calculated when all voltage sources are open circuited",
                "Thevenin equivalent is the voltage equivalent of the network are short circuited"
            ],
            "answer": "The Thevenin equivalent resistance is calculated when all voltage sources are open circuited"
        },
        {
            "question": "An initially uncharged capacitor C is connected in series with a resistor R. The combination is then connected to a battery of emf Vo. Sufficient time elapses so that the steady state is reached. Which of the following statement is NOT true?",
            "choices": [
                "The time constant is independent on Vo",
                "The final charge on C is independent on R",
                "The total thermal energy generated by R is independent of R",
                "The total thermal energy generated by R is independent of Vo",
                "The initial current is independent of C"
            ],
            "answer": "The total thermal energy generated by R is independent of R"
        },
        {
            "question": "If the magnetic flux through a certain region is changing with time ___.",
            "choices": [
                "A current must flow around the boundary",
                "An electric field must exist at the boundary",
                "A magnetic emf exist around the boundary",
                "Field must exist at the boundary"
            ],
            "answer": "A magnetic emf exist around the boundary"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the unit of relative permeability?",
            "choices": ["Henry", "Henry per meter", "Henry per meter^2", "it is dimension entity"],
            "answer": "it is dimension entity"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following materials have a very high permeabilities?",
            "choices": ["paramagnetic materials", "non-magnetic", "ferromagnetic materials", "diamagnetic materials"],
            "answer": "ferromagnetic materials"
        },
        {
            "question": "Two wattmeter method can be used to measure 3-phase power for",
            "choices": ["balanced and unbalanced load", "balanced load only", "unbalanced load only", "single phase load"],
            "answer": "balanced and unbalanced load"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a star connected system, the line current is",
            "choices": ["0.707 times the phase current", "equal to the phase current", "1.732 times the phase current", "1.414 times the phase current"],
            "answer": "equal to the phase current"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of modifying a high frequency carrier with the information to be transmitted is called",
            "choices": ["Multiplexing", "Detection", "Telemetry", "Modulation"],
            "answer": "Modulation"
        },
        {
            "question": "____ is a way of sending multiple signals or stream of information over a communications link over the same time in the form of a single, complex signal.",
            "choices": ["Multiplexing", "Mixing", "Telemetry", "Modulation"],
            "answer": "Multiplexing"
        },
        {
            "question": "The operation of fiber optic cable is based on the principle of",
            "choices": ["refraction", "reflection", "dispersion", "absorption"],
            "answer": "reflection"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a common application of fiber optic cable?",
            "choices": ["Computer network", "Closed circuit TV", "long distance telephone system", "consumer TV"],
            "answer": "consumer TV"
        },
        {
            "question": "In DC generators, lap winding is used for",
            "choices": ["low voltage, low current", "high voltage, high current", "low voltage, high current", "high voltage, low current"],
            "answer": "low voltage, high current"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of motor is used for food mixer?",
            "choices": ["Split phase", "Universal", "Shaded", "Compound shunt"],
            "answer": "Universal"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the device or part of transformer used to cool oil naturally?",
            "choices": ["Radiator", "Conservator", "Breather", "Bushing"],
            "answer": "Radiator"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is NOT a characteristic of an ideal transformer?",
            "choices": ["Finite permeability", "No losses", "Infinite permeability", "No leakage flux"],
            "answer": "Finite permeability"
        },
        {
            "question": "The short circuit in any windings of the transformer is the result of_",
            "choices": ["Impulse voltage", "Insulation failure", "Mechanical vibrations", "Loose connection"],
            "answer": "Impulse voltage"
        },
        {
            "question": "The connection of two single phase transformers for three phase operation is called?",
            "choices": ["Scott", "Delta Delta", "Open Delta", "Wye Delta"],
            "answer": "Open Delta"
        },
        {
            "question": "The primary of an ideal transformer has 100 turns and the secondary has 600 turns. What happens?",
            "choices": ["The power in the primary circuit is less than in the secondary circuit", "The currents in the two circuits are the same", "The voltage in the two circuits is the same", "The primary current is six times the secondary current"],
            "answer": "The primary current is six times the secondary current"
        },
        {
            "question": "If the torque angle d continuously increases, the system will become?",
            "choices": ["Stable", "Unstable", "Oscillatory stable", "Asymptotic stable"],
            "answer": "Unstable"
        },
        {
            "question": "A transformer has a reactance of 0.04 p.u. If the secondary of the transformer is short-circuited with normal voltage applied to the primary, the symmetrical short-circuit current will be?",
            "choices": ["4 times the full load current", "25 times the full load current", "29 times the full load current", "16 times the full load current"],
            "answer": "25 times the full load current"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is IEEE device number for AC Time Overcurrent Relay?",
            "choices": ["4.50", "52", "51", "67"],
            "answer": "51"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is used to model the transmission line? (I. T-network II. π-Network)",
            "choices": ["I only", "Either I or II", "II only", "Both I and II"],
            "answer": "Either I or II"
        },
        {
            "question": "For which of the following power plants are highly skilled engineers required for running the plants?",
            "choices": ["Nuclear power plants", "Gas turbine power plants", "Solar power plants", "Hydroelectric power plants"],
            "answer": "Nuclear power plants"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the power plant having the most expensive cost?",
            "choices": ["Nuclear", "Steam", "Hydro", "Diesel"],
            "answer": "Nuclear"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which power plant has the least maintenance and operating cost?",
            "choices": ["Diesel Power Plant", "Hydroelectric Power Plant", "Coal fired thermal Power Plant", "Oil Fired thermal Power Plant"],
            "answer": "Hydroelectric Power Plant"
        },
        {
            "question": "When the demand of consumers is not met by a power plant, it will resort to which of the following?",
            "choices": ["Load shedding", "Power factor improvement at all generators", "Penalizing high load consumers by increasing the charges for electricity", "Efficient plant operation"],
            "answer": "Load shedding"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which plant will take the least time in starting from cold condition to full load operation?",
            "choices": ["Nuclear Power Plant", "Steam Power Plant", "Hydroelectric Power Plant", "Gas Turbine Plant"],
            "answer": "Gas Turbine Plant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following relays are used for phase fault on long lines?",
            "choices": ["Impedance relay", "Reactance relay", "MHO relay", "Overcurrent relay"],
            "answer": "Impedance relay"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a load duration curve for an integrated power system, the uppermost crest represents the energy contributed by which one of the following?",
            "choices": ["Base Power Station", "Major Thermal Station", "Peaking Hydro or Gas Turbine", "Non-conventional Power Station"],
            "answer": "Non-conventional Power Station"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is not a consideration in surge arrester?",
            "choices": ["Arrester class", "Current rating", "Voltage rating", "Insulation coordination"],
            "answer": "Insulation coordination"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which power plant cannot have a single unit of 100 MW?",
            "choices": ["Hydroelectric Power Plant", "Diesel Power Plant", "Steam Power Plant", "Nuclear Power Plant"],
            "answer": "Diesel Power Plant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is not a qualification for a member of BEE?",
            "choices": ["Natural born Filipino", "Have BSEE degree", "At least 10 years practice", "At least 40 years old"],
            "answer": "At least 40 years old"
        },
        {
            "question": "The load (current) on a circuit breaker is generally not permitted to exceed what percentage of the rating of the circuit breaker?",
            "choices": ["100%", "125%", "150%", "80%"],
            "answer": "80%"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the minimum ampacity of feeders w/ motor and other load connected?",
            "choices": ["250% motor FL current plus other current", "125% motor FL current plus other current", "125% total current", "250% total current"],
            "answer": "125% motor FL current plus other current"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the normal bending radius from inner diameter edge of conduits with relation to diameter?",
            "choices": ["8-9 times", "6-7 times", "4-6 times", "3-4 times"],
            "answer": "8-9 times"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the allowable voltage drop of feeder used in lighting load?",
            "choices": ["2%", "5%", "3%", "10%"],
            "answer": "3%"
        },
        {
            "question": "The circuit conductors between the final overcurrent device protecting the circuit and the outlet(s)",
            "choices": ["Feeder", "Service lateral", "Branch circuit", "Service conductor"],
            "answer": "Branch circuit"
        },
        {
            "question": "A load is classified as considered continuous load if it operates _ hrs or more.",
            "choices": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Floor area of office building is 600 sqm and has general lighting load of 28VA per sqm. How many 230V, 20A lighting load circuit of the building?",
            "choices": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is not a qualification for member of BEE?",
            "choices": ["natural born Filipino", "have BSEE degree", "at least 10 yrs practice", "at least 40 years old"],
            "answer": "at least 40 years old"
        },
        {
            "question": "This MATLAB command clears all data and variables stored in memory",
            "choices": ["cle", "delete", "Clear", "deallocate"],
            "answer": "Clear"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tall growing plants refer to plants, vines and other plant species, which grow or have the potential to grow more than _ meter in height from the ground.",
            "choices": ["two (2)", "Three (3)", "Five (5)", "seven(7)"],
            "answer": "Three (3)"
        }

],



 "EE MODULE 4": [
 
    {
        "question": "If the shunt admittance of the transmission line is ignored, the torque angle at which maximum power will occur is",
        "choices": ["π/4", "-π/4", "π/2", "π"],
        "answer": "π/2"
    },
    {
        "question": "For load flow analysis transmission lines are represented",
        "choices": ["nominal T", "nominal π", "tuned power network", "ladder network"],
        "answer": "nominal π"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the torque angle continuously increases, system will become",
        "choices": ["stable", "unstable", "oscillatory stable", "asymptotic stable"],
        "answer": "unstable"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bus bar of the power system, whose voltage magnitude and angle is not known, is called",
        "choices": ["slack bus", "generator bus", "load bus", "PVI bus"],
        "answer": "load bus"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the transmission voltage is increased, the percentage resistance drop will",
        "choices": ["Increase", "decrease", "remain unchanged", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "decrease"
    },
    {
        "question": "The zero sequence magnetising current of a core type transformer compared to shell type is",
        "choices": ["lower", "higher", "equal", "none of these"],
        "answer": "higher"
    },
    {
        "question": "The power transmission capacity of the transmission line is",
        "choices": ["proportional to the square of the voltage", "inversely proportional to the voltage", "directly proportional to the voltage", "proportional to the cube of the voltage"],
        "answer": "proportional to the square of the voltage"
    },
    {
        "question": "The zero sequence current in ∆ winding of Y/∆ transformer is found",
        "choices": ["if neutral point of Y winding is not earthed", "if neutral point of Y winding is earthed", "whether the neutral point of the star winding is earthed or not earthed", "none of these"],
        "answer": "if neutral point of Y winding is earthed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Three phase short circuit current of an alternator will be",
        "choices": ["Zero", "maximum", "infinity", "very small"],
        "answer": "Zero"
    },
    {
        "question": "The zero sequence current will not flow in the",
        "choices": ["L-G fault", "L-L-G fault", "L-L fault", "L-L-L-G fault"],
        "answer": "L-L fault"
    },
    {
        "question": "The material used for fuse wire must have",
        "choices": ["low melting point and low specific resistance", "low melting point and high specific resistance", "high melting point and low specific resistance", "low melting point with any specific resistance"],
        "answer": "low melting point and high specific resistance"
    },
    {
        "question": "One conductor open in a three phase transmission line will develop",
        "choices": ["a series connection of sequence networks", "a parallel connection of sequence networks", "positive and negative sequence networks only", "none of these"],
        "answer": "a parallel connection of sequence networks"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Buchholz relay is used to protect the",
        "choices": ["alternators against all internal faults", "oil immersed transformers against all internal faults", "synchronous motors against all types of faults", "transmission line against all types of faults"],
        "answer": "oil immersed transformers against all internal faults"
    },
    {
        "question": "The steady state stability limit of a two-machine system depends on",
        "choices": ["per unit reactance of the power system", "power input", "power factor of the system", "per unit power input of the system"],
        "answer": "per unit reactance of the power system"
    },
    {
        "question": "Third harmonics current flows from the generator terminals through the system and returns by way of comparatively low zero-sequence reactance path to the neutral terminals will give rise to",
        "choices": ["overheating of generator", "overheating of generator and neutral resistor of earthing transformer", "overheating of earthing transformer only", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "overheating of generator and neutral resistor of earthing transformer"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a voltage controlled bus, following quantities are specified",
        "choices": ["P and Q", "P and |V|", "Q and |V|", "P and S"],
        "answer": "P and |V|"
    },
    {
        "question": "To protect the power transformer (Y -Y, with neutral grounded) against fault, the CT will have",
        "choices": ["∆ - ∆ connection", "∆ - Y connection", "Y - ∆ connection", "Y - Y connection"],
        "answer": "∆ - ∆ connection"
    },
    {
        "question": "At steady-state, positive, negative, and zero sequence impedance with Zf = 0, always follow the relations:",
        "choices": ["Z1 > Z2 > Z0", "Z1 < Z2 < Z0", "Z0 < Z1 < Z2", "none of these"],
        "answer": "Z1 > Z2 > Z0"
    },
    {
        "question": "The class C insulation can withstand",
        "choices": ["180°C", "150°C", "200°C", "105°C"],
        "answer": "180°C"
    },
    {
        "question": "The percent bias for a generator protection lies between",
        "choices": ["5 to 10", "10 to 15", "15 to 20", "2 - 10"],
        "answer": "5 to 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the transformers",
        "choices": ["high tension winding is used near the core", "high tension winding is used away from the core", "low tension winding is used near the core", "low tension winding is used away from the core"],
        "answer": "high tension winding is used near the core"
    },
    {
        "question": "A shunt fault is characterized by",
        "choices": ["increase in frequency, power factor and current", "increase in current reduction, frequency and p.f.", "increase in current and frequency but reduction in p.f.", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "increase in current reduction, frequency and p.f."
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of series capacitor on a transmission line is to improve the",
        "choices": ["steady state stability", "transient stability", "both A and B", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "both A and B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most economic load on an overhead line is",
        "choices": ["greater than the natural load", "less than the natural load", "equal to the natural load", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "greater than the natural load"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two transmission lines of the surge impedance of 600 ohms each is linked by a cable. What should be the surge impedance of the cable if there were no reflection at the junction?",
        "choices": ["300 ohms", "30 ohms", "600 ohms", "60 ohms"],
        "answer": "600 ohms"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most economical load on an underground cable is",
        "choices": ["equal to the surge loading", "less than the surge loading", "greater than its surge loading", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "less than the surge loading"
    },
    {
        "question": "For 11 kV underground system, it is possible to work upon a length of",
        "choices": ["800 miles", "100 miles", "400 miles", "10 miles"],
        "answer": "100 miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Capacitor switching is easily done with",
        "choices": ["oil circuit breaker", "air blast circuit breaker", "vacuum circuit breaker", "both A and B"],
        "answer": "vacuum circuit breaker"
    },
    {
        "question": "Series capacitor are used to",
        "choices": ["improve the line voltage", "compensate for line inductive reactance", "compensate for line capacitive reactance", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "compensate for line inductive reactance"
    },
    {
        "question": "For rural electrification with complex network, it is preferable to use:",
        "choices": ["oil circuit breaker", "reactance relay", "vacuum circuit breaker", "M.O.C.B"],
        "answer": "vacuum circuit breaker"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following relays are used for phase fault on long line?",
        "choices": ["impedance relays", "reactance relays", "MHO relays", "Over current relays"],
        "answer": "MHO relays"
    },
    {
        "question": "An overhead high voltage transmission line with series compensation is protected using",
        "choices": ["mho relay", "impedance relay", "reactance relay", "none of these"],
        "answer": "none of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a detection of the occurence of the severe synchronising power surges",
        "choices": ["impedance relays are best suited", "reactance relays are best suited", "MHO relays are best suited", "split-phase relays are best suited"],
        "answer": "MHO relays are best suited"
    },
    {
        "question": "The size of conductor on EHV lines is obtained based on",
        "choices": ["current density", "voltage drop", "corona", "both A and B"],
        "answer": "corona"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the height of the transmission tower is decreased, the capacitance of the line will",
        "choices": ["increase", "decrease", "remain same", "decrease exponentially"],
        "answer": "increase"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transmission line is operated with power angle in the range",
        "choices": ["10°-20°", "30°-45°", "60°-75°", "65°- 80°"],
        "answer": "30°-45°"
    },
    {
        "question": "AC system has the following disadvantages over DC sytem",
        "choices": ["skin effect exists", "line regulation is more", "charging current exists", "proximity effect exists"],
        "answer": "charging current exists"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a lumped inductive load, with increase in supply frequency",
        "choices": ["P and Q increase", "P increases and Q decreases", "P decreases and Q increases", "P and Q decreases"],
        "answer": "P decreases and Q increases"
    },
    {
        "question": "The voltage regulation is an important factor for the design of",
        "choices": ["generator", "motor", "feeder", "transmission line"],
        "answer": "feeder"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gas turbines can pick up from cold in about",
        "choices": ["2 minutes", "30 minutes", "45 minutes", "60 minutes"],
        "answer": "2 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following parameter can be neglected for a short line?",
        "choices": ["resistance", "inductance", "reactance", "capacitance"],
        "answer": "capacitance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Voltage magnitude of a particular bus can be controlled by controling the",
        "choices": ["active power of the bus", "reactive power of the bus", "phase angle", "both B and C"],
        "answer": "reactive power of the bus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following breaker has high reliability and minimum maintenance?",
        "choices": ["oil circuit breaker", "airblast circuit breaker", "vacuum circuit breaker", "SF6 circuit breaker"],
        "answer": "SF6 circuit breaker"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convergeance of the transmission load flow is always assured in case of",
        "choices": ["Newton-Raphson method", "Gauss-seidel method", "Gauss method", "both A and B"],
        "answer": "both A and B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following insulator will be selected for high voltage application?",
        "choices": ["strain type", "disc type", "suspension type", "pin type"],
        "answer": "suspension type"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pick the corect loss coefficiency for two bus system",
        "choices": [
            "B11= 0.02, B22= 0.05, B12= 0.01, B21= 0.03",
            "B11 = 0.02, B22=0.04, B12 = 0.01, B21 =0.001",
            "B11=0.03, B22 =0.005, B12 = 0.001, B21=-0.001",
            "B11= 0.04, B22 = 0.05, B12 = 0.03, B21 =0.04"
        ],
        "answer": "B11=0.03, B22 =0.005, B12 = 0.001, B21=-0.001"
    },
    {
        "question": "The strain type insulators used when",
        "choices": ["the transmission line is dead ended", "the direction of transmission line changes", "The transmission line is short", "A or B"],
        "answer": "A or B"
    },
    {
        "question": "The inertia constant H of a machine of 200 MVA is 2 pu, its value corresponding to 400 MVA will be",
        "choices": ["4.0", "2.0", "1.0", "0.50"],
        "answer": "1.0"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the capacitance of the transmission line is increased, the transmitted power will",
        "choices": ["remain same", "Increase", "decrease", "tend to zero at the receiving end"],
        "answer": "Increase"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the stable operation of interconnected system, the passive element that can be used as interconnecting elements is.",
        "choices": ["reactor", "capacitor", "resistor", "none of these"],
        "answer": "reactor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Booster transformers are used to increase the voltage at _______ of a transmission line",
        "choices": ["sending end", "receiving end", "intermediate points", "the centre"],
        "answer": "intermediate points"
    },
    {
        "question": "The voltage regulation Re of a transmission line voltage |V| is",
        "choices": ["Re α |V|²", "Re α |V|", "Re α 1/|V|²", "Re α 1/|V|"],
        "answer": "Re α 1/|V|"
    },
    {
        "question": "Long transmission line has a surge impedance of approximately",
        "choices": ["31.4 ohms", "75 ohms", "282 ohms", "400 ohms"],
        "answer": "400 ohms"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transfer of real power between interconnected stations is affected by",
        "choices": ["reactance", "capacitance", "inductance", "all of these"],
        "answer": "capacitance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shunt conductance in power transmission lines is due to leakage over the",
        "choices": ["conducors", "insulators", "poles", "jumpers"],
        "answer": "insulators"
    },
    {
        "question": "Voltage gradient in a conductor is highest at its",
        "choices": ["centre", "surface", "circle with half the radius", "axial line along its average radial circle"],
        "answer": "surface"
    },
    {
        "question": "Voltage gradient in a cable is highest at the",
        "choices": ["center of the conductor", "surface of the conductor", "surface of the sheath", "all of these"],
        "answer": "surface of the conductor"
    },
    {
        "question": "The real part of propagation constant of a transmission line is",
        "choices": ["phase constant", "attenuation constant", "stability constant", "reliabity factor"],
        "answer": "attenuation constant"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a span of length of 2l, horizontal tension at supports as T weight of the conductor per unit length is w, the maximum value af sag wil be",
        "choices": ["2wt/T", "2wt²/T", "wt/2T", "wt²/2T"],
        "answer": "wt²/2T"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sag of the transmission line addected by",
        "choices": ["its own weight and weight of the ice", "temperature and wind condition", "both A and B", "either of A or B"],
        "answer": "both A and B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most commonly used supports for high tension lines is",
        "choices": ["Wooden poles", "steel poles", "cross bars", "latticed steel poles"],
        "answer": "latticed steel poles"
    },
    {
        "question": "When horizontal tension H increases by 20%, the tension T changes by a",
        "choices": ["decrease of 20%", "decrease of 10%", "no change", "increase of 20%"],
        "answer": "increase of 20%"
    },
    {
        "question": "A transmission Iine is a circuit with",
        "choices": ["distributed parameters of R, L,C and G", "lumps of R and L", "lumps of L and C", "both B and C"],
        "answer": "distributed parameters of R, L,C and G"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inductance of a conductor due to its internal flux is",
        "choices": ["2πx10^-7 H/m", "(2πx10^-7)^-1 H/m", "2πx10^-7/7 H/m", "0.5x10^-7 H/m"],
        "answer": "0.5x10^-7 H/m"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inductance between two conductors of diameter D1 and D2 is",
        "choices": ["½x10^-7 x (D2/D1) H/m", "2x10^-7 ln(D2/D1) H/m", "10^-7 x ln(D2/D1) H/m", "2πx10^-7 ln(D2/D1) H/m"],
        "answer": "2x10^-7 ln(D2/D1) H/m"
    },
    {
        "question": "A conductor has seven identical strands of r = 1 cm each. The GMR of the conductor is",
        "choices": ["7 cm", "3.5 cm", "2.177 cm", "0.177 cm"],
        "answer": "2.177 cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ACSR conductor has (n- 1) layers around its single centre strands, the total number of strands will be.",
        "choices": ["3n² + 3n + 1", "3n² - 3n -1", "3n² + 3n - 1", "3n² - 3n + 1"],
        "answer": "3n² - 3n + 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ACSR oonductor has seven steel strands, it is surrounded by twenty four aluminum conductors, it is specified as",
        "choices": ["31 ACSR", "31/7 ACSR", "7/31 ACSR", "24/7 ACSR"],
        "answer": "24/7 ACSR"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of inductance per conductor in three phase line is ..... times the loop inductance for single phase lines",
        "choices": ["⅓", "½", "1", "2"],
        "answer": "½"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the conductor of a three-phase circuit are not spaced equilaterally, the transposition is done to.",
        "choices": ["decrease the line inductance per phase", "minimize the effect adjoining communication circuit", "balance the three phases of the circuit", "both A and B"],
        "answer": "balance the three phases of the circuit"
    },
    {
        "question": "In EHV lines, the high voltage gradient at the conductors is reduced by",
        "choices": ["transposing the lines", "increasing the height of the supporting towers", "two or more conductors per phase in close proximity and increasing the spacing between the phases", "all of these"],
        "answer": "two or more conductors per phase in close proximity and increasing the spacing between the phases"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission line inductance contributed by",
        "choices": ["the current in the conductor", "the current in other conductor", "extra high voltage in between the conductors", "all of these"],
        "answer": "the current in other conductor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulating transformers are used in power system to control",
        "choices": ["power factor", "load flow", "voltage", "none of these"],
        "answer": "load flow"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ratio of capacitance of line to neutral and line to line capacitance of a transmission line having two conductors is",
        "choices": ["¼", "½", "1.0", "2.0"],
        "answer": "2.0"
    },
    {
        "question": "Charging current due to capacitance C when a single phase line is transmitting power at a voltage v and frequency w is",
        "choices": ["-v/jwc", "jwv/c", "v/c", "jwcv"],
        "answer": "jwcv"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rise of temperature in transmission line",
        "choices": [
            "increase the stress and the length",
            "decrease the stress and increase the length",
            "decrease the stress and the length",
            "increase the stress and decrease the length"
        ],
        "answer": "decrease the stress and increase the length"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of earth alters the",
        "choices": ["electric field of the line", "capacitance of the line", "both A and B", "inductance of the line"],
        "answer": "both A and B"
    },
    {
        "question": "The skin effect in conductors is due to non-unifom distribution of current in it and major portion of the current is near the..... of the conductor.",
        "choices": ["Surface", "centre", "axis", "radial lines"],
        "answer": "Surface"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effective resistance of conductor is increased by",
        "choices": ["skin effect", "proximity effect", "corona effect", "both A and B"],
        "answer": "both A and B"
    },
    {
        "question": "In both skin effect and proximity effect",
        "choices": [
            "the effective internal reactance of the conductor gets decreased",
            "their effect depends upon conductor size d, frequency f, resistivity p. and permeability μp",
            "the effect is negligible at power frequency and small conductors, but the effect is large for higher frequency and big conductors",
            "all of these"
        ],
        "answer": "all of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "A two terminal pair of network of a transmission line can be represented by a",
        "choices": ["π - network", "T - network", "either A or B", "tree network"],
        "answer": "either A or B"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a short transmission line",
        "choices": ["Vr = Vs - IsZ", "A=D=1", "C = 0 and B = Z", "all of these"],
        "answer": "all of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "A medium transmission line has length over 80 Km and upto 250 Km has negligible",
        "choices": ["resistance", "inductance", "conductance", "capacitance"],
        "answer": "conductance"
    },
    {
        "question": "The characteristics impedance of a loss-less overhead line has a value of",
        "choices": ["400 to 600 ohms", "40 to 60 ohms", "100 to 200 ohms", "30 to 300 ohms"],
        "answer": "400 to 600 ohms"
    },
    {
        "question": "The characteristics impedance of loss-less cable is",
        "choices": ["400 to 600 ohms", "40 to 60 ohms", "100 to 200 ohms", "30 to 300 ohms"],
        "answer": "40 to 60 ohms"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ferranti effect states that the receiving end voltage on no load is",
        "choices": [
            "equal to that at the sending end",
            "less than that at the sending end",
            "more than that at the sending end",
            "either B or C"
        ],
        "answer": "more than that at the sending end"
    },
    {
        "question": "At no load, the loss in a long transmission line is",
        "choices": ["0", "½RI²0", "⅓RI²0", "¼RI²0"],
        "answer": "⅓RI²0"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advantages of constant voltage transmission are:",
        "choices": [
            "improve power factor at heavy loads",
            "same voltage is maintained at all loads",
            "increased power transmission over long distance",
            "all of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Commonly used equivalent network of a transmission line is",
        "choices": ["π", "T", "Ladder network", "either A or B"],
        "answer": "π"
    },
    {
        "question": "In terms of ABCD constants, the characteristics impedance of overhead transmission is",
        "choices": ["(A/D)½", "(B/C)½", "(AB/CD)½", "(C/D)½"],
        "answer": "(AB/CD)½"
    },
    {
        "question": "The units of B and C are respectively",
        "choices": ["mho, mho", "ohm, ohm", "mho, ohm", "ohm, mho"],
        "answer": "ohm, mho"
    },
    {
        "question": "To increase transmitted power over line",
        "choices": ["increase its capacitance", "increase its line voltage", "decrease its line inductance", "any of these"],
        "answer": "any of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "A transmission line has value of its A constant as",
        "choices": ["zero", "nearly zero", "unity", "nearly equal unity"],
        "answer": "nearly equal unity"
    },
    {
        "question": "When two lines having constant A1, B1, C1, D1 and A2, B2, C2, D2 are cascades in series, the resultant value of A constant will be...",
        "choices": ["A1A2 + B1C2", "A1 + A2", "A1A2", "A1D2 + A2D1"],
        "answer": "A1A2 + B1C2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Corona always causes",
        "choices": ["insulation failure", "system faults", "radio interference", "all of these"],
        "answer": "radio interference"
    },
    {
        "question": "Corona loss is more in",
        "choices": ["unstranded conductor", "ACSR", "stranded conductor", "transposed conductor"],
        "answer": "unstranded conductor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Load that depends on the supply frequency is of",
        "choices": ["fan type", "heating and welding type", "synchronous condenser", "centrifugal pumps"],
        "answer": "centrifugal pumps"
    },
    {
        "question": "The inertia constants of two machines are respectively 30 and 42 MJ per MVA. When the change in frequency due to change in load in first machine is 12 Hz, the change in the second machine frequency will be.",
        "choices": ["10 Hz", "12 Hz", "15 Hz", "42 Hz"],
        "answer": "10 Hz"
    },
    {
        "question": "For costs and safety, the outdoor substations are installed for voltages above",
        "choices": ["6.6 KV", "11 KV", "33 KV", "132 KV"],
        "answer": "33 KV"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lamp flicker in secondary distribution system is controlled by",
        "choices": ["transforming banking", "series capacitor", "both A and B", "induction regulator"],
        "answer": "both A and B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transient stability can be improved by the use of",
        "choices": ["high inertia machines", "high speed governors", "fast acting voltage regulating system", "all of the above"],
        "answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a line to line fault occurs, the SC current of an alternator depends upon its.",
        "choices": ["substransient reactance", "transient reactance", "short circuit resistance", "synchrounous reactance"],
        "answer": "synchrounous reactance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Maximum SC current occurs due to",
        "choices": ["dead short circuit", "L - L fault", "L - G fault", "L - L - G fault"],
        "answer": "dead short circuit"
    },
    {
        "question": "Causes of faults in power system",
        "choices": ["lightning and tree falling on line", "Switching", "storm, wind and jumping conductors", "all of these"],
        "answer": "all of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "In case of L - G fault, the fault current is equal to",
        "choices": ["3Ra/Z1+Z2+Z0", "3Ea/Zn", "0", "Ea/3(Z1+Z2)"],
        "answer": "3Ra/Z1+Z2+Z0"
    },
    {
        "question": "The various power system faults can be arranged in the order of increasing severity is",
        "choices": ["L-G, L-L, L-L-G, L-L-L-G", "L-L-G, L-L-L-G, L-G, L-L", "L-L-L-G, L-L-L-G, L-L, L-G", "L-L-L-G, L-L-L-G, L-G, L-L"],
        "answer": "L-G, L-L, L-L-G, L-L-L-G"
    },
    {
        "question": "The negative sequence component of a voltage is equal to",
        "choices": [
            "positive sequence component in reverse direction",
            "complex conjugate of positive sequence component",
            "multiple of operator \"B\" with positive sequence component",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "answer": "complex conjugate of positive sequence component"
    },
    {
        "question": "In circuit breakers, the arc is initiated by the process of",
        "choices": ["field emission", "thermal emission", "either A or B", "oil in the circuit breaker"],
        "answer": "either A or B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wave trap is used to trap waves of",
        "choices": ["higher frequencies entering generator or transformers units", "Power frequencies", "either A or B at a time", "none of these"],
        "answer": "higher frequencies entering generator or transformers units"
    },
    {
        "question": "Underground neutral transmission system is not recommended because of system",
        "choices": ["insulation being over stressed due to over voltages", "being inadequately protected against ground fault", "insulation over stressed may lead to failure and subsequent phase to phase faults", "all of the above"],
        "answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a 400 kV system, the capacity of lightning arrester is",
        "choices": ["10 KA", "800 A", "1.6 KA", "9 KA"],
        "answer": "10 KA"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gap length of rod type surge diverter used for 132 kV line should be",
        "choices": ["65 cm", "23 cm", "130 cm", "46 cm"],
        "answer": "65 cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the open circuited end of a transmission line, the reflection coefficient is",
        "choices": ["Ro", "0", "1/Ro", "1.0"],
        "answer": "1.0"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a wave propagate on a transmission line, it suffers reflection several times at",
        "choices": ["sending end", "sending and other end", "load end", "tapping"],
        "answer": "sending and other end"
    },
    {
        "question": "Advantages of grounding are:",
        "choices": ["\"arcing ground\" phenomena is eliminated", "earth fault current can be utilized to operate relays", "both A and B", "provide symmetry of the line impedance"],
        "answer": "both A and B"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the fuel input to the prime mover of an alternator is increased, it increases its",
        "choices": ["power factor", "torque angle", "power output", "all of these"],
        "answer": "power output"
    },
    {
        "question": "In power system, the purpose of an inter-connector is to",
        "choices": ["reduce the SC current", "improve the stability margin", "allow the flow of current from one generator to another", "all of the above"],
        "answer": "allow the flow of current from one generator to another"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conductor size of a feeder is determined on the basis of",
        "choices": ["the amount of current it has to carry", "the voltage across the feeder", "the length of the feeder", "the power factor of the load"],
        "answer": "the amount of current it has to carry"
    },
    {
        "question": "A thermal power plant has an efficiency cost is",
        "choices": ["20%", "30%", "40%", "60%"],
        "answer": "30%"
    },
    {
        "question": "The generating station with minimum running cost is",
        "choices": ["hydro power station", "the voltage across the feeder", "thermal power station", "diesel power station"],
        "answer": "hydro power station"
    },
    {
        "question": "Power plant having the maximum efficiency is",
        "choices": ["thermal", "hydro", "diesel", "nuclear"],
        "answer": "nuclear"
    },
    {
        "question": "Maximum speed of modern turbo-alternator is",
        "choices": ["1000 rpm", "3000 rpm", "1500 rpm", "1500 rpm"],
        "answer": "3000 rpm"
    },
    {
        "question": "The charging current in the cables",
        "choices": ["lags the voltage by 90°", "leads the voltage by 90°", "in-phase with the voltage", "none of these"],
        "answer": "leads the voltage by 90°"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tappings in on-load tap changing transformer are provided on",
        "choices": ["LV side", "HV side", "both LV and HV side", "all of these"],
        "answer": "HV side"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cost of the power generation will decrease when the load factor",
        "choices": ["decreases", "increases", "remain constant", "none of these"],
        "answer": "increases"
    },
    {
        "question": "A telephone line has a surge impedance of",
        "choices": ["50 ohm", "60 ohm", "75 ohm", "200 ohm"],
        "answer": "200 ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "The dielectric strength of air at 76 cm of Hg and 25°C is",
        "choices": ["30 KV/cm", "21.1 KV r.m.s./cm", "21.1 KV r.m.s./m", "21.1 KV/cm"],
        "answer": "21.1 KV r.m.s./m"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a transmission line, the conductors take the form of",
        "choices": ["parabola", "hyperbola", "catenary", "semi circle"],
        "answer": "catenary"
    },
    {
        "question": "Water is used only for cooling purposes in",
        "choices": ["nuclear power station", "diesel power station", "thermal power station", "gas-turbine power station"],
        "answer": "diesel power station"
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of power station at Bhakra is",
        "choices": ["nuclear", "thermal", "hydro", "diesel"],
        "answer": "hydro"
    },
    {
        "question": "Turbo-alternators usually have",
        "choices": ["2 poles", "6 poles", "10 poles", "4 poles"],
        "answer": "2 poles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alternators installed in hydro power station, are of",
        "choices": ["low speed", "high speed", "medium speed", "very high speed"],
        "answer": "medium speed"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ACSR conductor of size 48/7 means that",
        "choices": ["It has 48 strands of steel and 7 strands of aluminum", "it has 7 strands of steel and 48 strands of aluminum", "the conductor has 55 strands", "the conductor has 41 strands"],
        "answer": "it has 7 strands of steel and 48 strands of aluminum"
    },
    {
        "question": "A double circuit transmission line will have _________ conductors including earth conductors.",
        "choices": ["6", "9", "8", "4"],
        "answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "question": "In D.C. transmission there is no skin effect",
        "choices": ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        "answer": "FALSE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydro power stations are used as _________ load stations",
        "choices": ["base load", "Peak", "Regulating", "Reserve"],
        "answer": "base load"
    },
    {
        "question": "Water hammer is developed in",
        "choices": ["Turbine", "Penstock", "Dam", "Generator"],
        "answer": "Penstock"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reflection factor for a short-circuited transmission line is",
        "choices": ["Unity", "0.5", "0.9", "0.8"],
        "answer": "Unity"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of diversity factor is",
        "choices": ["less than one", "greater than one", "equal to one", "less than half"],
        "answer": "greater than one"
    },
    {
        "question": "The per capita consumption of electrical energy in India is",
        "choices": ["more than 150 kwh", "less than 150 kwh", "less than 50 kwh", "none of these"],
        "answer": "more than 150 kwh"
    },
    {
        "question": "The percentage of electric energy consumed on a world wide basis is",
        "choices": ["80%", "75%", "30%", "none of these"],
        "answer": "30%"
    },
    {
        "question": "In India, the thermal generation is about",
        "choices": ["80%", "40%", "65%", "50%"],
        "answer": "65%"
    },
    {
        "question": "The turbine used for high head in hydro plant is",
        "choices": ["Francis turbine", "Kaplan turbine", "Pelton turbine", "none of these"],
        "answer": "Pelton turbine"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pelton wheel is",
        "choices": ["axial flow impulse turbine", "pressure turbine", "reaction turbine", "none of these"],
        "answer": "axial flow impulse turbine"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum head upto which a pelton-wheel can be easily designed is",
        "choices": ["150 m", "1800 m", "1000 m", "300 m"],
        "answer": "1800 m"
    },
    {
        "question": "If low head and large quantity of water are available, a power engineer should select",
        "choices": ["Kaplan turbine", "Pelton turbine", "Francis turbine", "none of these"],
        "answer": "Kaplan turbine"
    },
    {
        "question": "The electric energy is directly generated by the combustion of fuel on a stationary device by a process, called",
        "choices": ["Magnetohydro dynamic process", "thermal process", "nuclear fission process", "all of these"],
        "answer": "Magnetohydro dynamic process"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gas turbine is",
        "choices": ["more economical to a conventional steam plant", "unable to maintain flat voltage profile in the system even it is used as synchrounous compensator", "able to meet sudden peaks of system load", "all of the above"],
        "answer": "able to meet sudden peaks of system load"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conductors used in pràctice for transmission line is stranded for",
        "choices": ["providing necessary flexibility for stringing", "reducing the effective resistance", "preventing unwinding", "all of the above"],
        "answer": "providing necessary flexibility for stringing"
    },
    {
        "question": "The per unit impedances of a transformer referred from the primary and secondary side",
        "choices": ["are not equal", "are equal", "are varying according to the base voltage and MVA", "both B and C"],
        "answer": "are equal"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tuned power lines are impracticable from the point of view of cost and efficiency",
        "choices": ["because of long distance transmission line is required", "because of Ferranti effect", "because of proximity effect", "because of skin effect"],
        "answer": "because of long distance transmission line is required"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sag of a transmission line with 50m span in 1 m. What will be the sag if the height of the transmission line is increased by 20%",
        "choices": ["1.2 m", "2 m", "1.25 m", "1 m"],
        "answer": "1 m"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 50 hz, 4 pole alternator rated at 20 MVA, 13.2 kV has an inertia constant H=4KW -sec/KVA. The K.E. stored in the rotor at synchronous speed is",
        "choices": ["80 KJ", "MJ", "40 MJ", "20 MJ"],
        "answer": "MJ"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following method may be used to inject reactive power in the transmission line?",
        "choices": ["series capacitor", "shunt capacitor", "shunt reactor", "voltage regulator"],
        "answer": "shunt capacitor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Corona loss is less when the shape of the conductor is",
        "choices": ["circular", "flat", "square", "oval"],
        "answer": "circular"
    },
    {
        "question": "The guard wire is firmly connected with",
        "choices": ["neutral wire", "phase wire", "cross arm", "earth wire"],
        "answer": "earth wire"
    },
    {
        "question": "A system is said to be effectively grounded if its",
        "choices": ["Xo/X1 > 3.0", "Ro/X1 > 2.0", "neutral is grounded directly", "Xo/X1 < 3.0"],
        "answer": "Xo/X1 < 3.0"
    },
    {
        "question": "The load must not be connected directly on",
        "choices": ["transmission line", "distributor", "service mains", "L.T. 220 volt line"],
        "answer": "transmission line"
    },
    {
        "question": "If S is the loss angle of the cable, its power factor is",
        "choices": ["sin S", "cos S", "power factor is independent of S", "sin 2 S"],
        "answer": "sin S"
    },
    {
        "question": "Generally the porcelain insulators are glazed because",
        "choices": ["it helps in gliding down of water easily", "it improves its apperance", "it prevents the absorbing tendency of gases and water vapours", "it increases its mechanical strength"],
        "answer": "it helps in gliding down of water easily"
    },
    {
        "question": "A synchronous machine has higher capacity for",
        "choices": ["leading p.f.", "lagging p.f.", "its depends upon the p.f. of the load", "it does not depend upon the pf. of the machine"],
        "answer": "leading p.f."
    },
    {
        "question": "In case of pin type insulators, the petticoats are provided to",
        "choices": ["improve its appearance", "to drip out the rain water and to increase the possible conducting length of the path", "to protect the stud from sun lighting", "to protect the stud from wind pressure"],
        "answer": "to drip out the rain water and to increase the possible conducting length of the path"
    },
    {
        "question": "The positve sequence component of the voltage at the point of fault is zero when it is a",
        "choices": ["three-phase fault", "L-L fault", "L-L-G fault", "L-G fault"],
        "answer": "three-phase fault"
    },
    {
        "question": "Up to which voltage, the pin insulators are preferred?",
        "choices": ["25 kV", "11 kV", "500 kV", "66 kV"],
        "answer": "25 kV"
    },
    {
        "question": "The magnetising inrush current in a transformer is rich in",
        "choices": ["2nd harmonics", "7-th harmonics", "3rd harmonics", "5-th hamonics"],
        "answer": "2nd harmonics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the effect which resulted because of the size of conductor, frequency and the specific resistance of the conducting material.",
        "choices": ["Corona effect", "Skin effect", "Proximity effect", "Thomson effect"],
        "answer": "Skin effect"
    },
    {
        "question": "The solution of co-ordination equations takes into account",
        "choices": ["all the system and operation constraints", "all the operational constraints", "all the system constraints", "none of these"],
        "answer": "none of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the specific resistance of the conductor is increased, what effect does it result on the skin effect?",
        "choices": ["remain same", "decreasing", "increasing", "none of the above"],
        "answer": "decreasing"
    },
    {
        "question": "The incremental transmission loss of a plant is",
        "choices": ["always positive", "always negative", "can be positive or negative", "complex quantity"],
        "answer": "can be positive or negative"
    },
    {
        "question": "The capacitor bank is installed",
        "choices": ["to improve the power factor and voltage magnitude", "to decrease the power factor and voltage magnitude", "to improve the power factor", "to improve the voltage magnitude only"],
        "answer": "to improve the power factor and voltage magnitude"
    },
    {
        "question": "Load flow study is carried out for",
        "choices": ["fault calculations", "stability studies", "system planning", "state estimate"],
        "answer": "system planning"
    },
    {
        "question": "The disadvantages of transmission line as compared to cable system are",
        "choices": ["atmospheric hazards", "atmospheric hazards, exposures to lightning", "interference of telecommunication circuits", "atmospheric hazards like smoke, ice fumes, exposures to lightning, interference of telecommunication circuits etc."],
        "answer": "atmospheric hazards like smoke, ice fumes, exposures to lightning, interference of telecommunication circuits etc."
    },
    {
        "question": "Diagonal elements of Y-matrix are strengthened by adding",
        "choices": ["shunt reactors", "shunt capacitors", "loads", "all of these"],
        "answer": "shunt reactors"
    },
    {
        "question": "The safe working life of the underground cable is taken as",
        "choices": ["2 years", "5 years", "40 years", "100 years"],
        "answer": "40 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "A long transmission line has certain values of parameters A, B, C, D, if the length is made 100 km thus the parameter",
        "choices": ["A increases B decreases", "A and B both increase", "A and B decreases", "A decreases B increases"],
        "answer": "A increases B decreases"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pole mounting substations are also known as",
        "choices": ["outdoor type", "indoor type", "basement type", "open type"],
        "answer": "outdoor type"
    },
    {
        "question": "Three phase transformers which can not be connected in parallel are",
        "choices": ["Y-Y with ∆-∆", "Y-∆ with ∆-Y", "Y-Y with Y-∆", "B and C"],
        "answer": "Y-Y with Y-∆"
    },
    {
        "question": "A circuit breaker serves the purpose of",
        "choices": ["switching-on and switching-off under normal working conditions", "protecting the circuit under abnormal condition of load", "protecting the circuit under faulty conditions", "all of the above"],
        "answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main consideration for higher operating voltage of transmission is to",
        "choices": ["increase the efficiency", "reduce power loss", "increase power transfer capability", "both A and B"],
        "answer": "increase power transfer capability"
    },
    {
        "question": "Base load plants are designed to supply power at",
        "choices": ["low capital cost and low operating cost", "high capital cost and low operating cost", "low capital cost and high operating cost", "high capital cost and high operating cost"],
        "answer": "high capital cost and low operating cost"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the effect of earth is taken into account, then the capacitance of line to ground",
        "choices": ["decrease", "increases", "remains unchange", "become infinite"],
        "answer": "increases"
    },
    {
        "question": "Peak load plants are designed to supply power at",
        "choices": ["low capital cost and low operating cost", "high capital cost and low operating cost", "low capital cost and high operating cost", "high capital cost and high operating cost"],
        "answer": "low capital cost and high operating cost"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a Y-∆ transformer Y-side grounded, the zero sequence current",
        "choices": ["has no path to ground", "exists in the lines on the ∆-side", "exists in the line on the Y-side", "exists in the lines on both Y and ∆ sides"],
        "answer": "exists in the line on the Y-side"
    },
    {
        "question": "The overall efficiency of thermal power plant is low due to low efficiency of",
        "choices": ["steam turbine and condenser", "boiler", "alternator", "economizer"],
        "answer": "steam turbine and condenser"
    },
    {
        "question": "Corona loss can be reduced by the use of hollow conductor because",
        "choices": ["the current density is reduced", "eddy current in the conductor is eliminated", "for a given cross-section, the radius of the conductor is increased", "of better ventilation in the conductor"],
        "answer": "for a given cross-section, the radius of the conductor is increased"
    },
    {
        "question": "In practice, the cost of energy transmission is minimum for",
        "choices": ["natural gas power plants", "diesel power plants", "nuclear power plant", "steam power plant"],
        "answer": "steam power plant"
    },
    {
        "question": "Convergence characteristics of Gauss-Seidel method is",
        "choices": ["linear", "super linear", "quadratic", "cubic"],
        "answer": "linear"
    },
    {
        "question": "The peak load demand of an industrial area is met by",
        "choices": ["nuclear power plant", "storage batteries", "diesel power plant", "steam power plant"],
        "answer": "diesel power plant"
    },
    {
        "question": "FDLF method is suitable for",
        "choices": ["high voltage transmission system", "medium voltage transmission system", "distribution system", "none of these"],
        "answer": "high voltage transmission system"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main objective of tariff is to distribute equitably the cost of",
        "choices": ["installation and fuel", "power transmission and distribution", "both A and B", "supplying energy among various classifications of use"],
        "answer": "supplying energy among various classifications of use"
    },
    {
        "question": "If real power demand is suddenly increased, frequency of the system will",
        "choices": ["increase", "decrease", "remains same", "none of these"],
        "answer": "decrease"
    },
    {
        "question": "Factors involved in fixing tariff are",
        "choices": [
            "secured return from each consumer",
            "simplicity, cheapness and easy explainability",
            "Incentives to consumers and charge according to use",
            "all of these"
        ],
        "answer": "all of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "Disadvantage of low power factor are",
        "choices": [
            "high rating of generating. transmitting and distributing equipments",
            "large voltage drop and poor voltage regulation",
            "large copper loss and high capital cost",
            "all of these"
        ],
        "answer": "all of these"
    },
    {
        "question": "Demand factor for a domestic fan and refrigerator is approximately",
        "choices": [
            "0.75 and 1.0",
            "0.6 and 0.75",
            "0.50 and 0.50",
            "0.33 and 0.73"
        ],
        "answer": "0.75 and 1.0"
    },
    {
        "question": "The surge impedance of a transmission line differs from its characteristics impedance, as surge impedance consider line",
        "choices": [
            "capacitance to be zero",
            "resistance of finite value",
            "inductance to be zero",
            "both C and A"
        ],
        "answer": "resistance of finite value"
    },
    {
        "question": "The power factor of receiving end of transmission line is",
        "choices": [
            "equal to power factor of sending end",
            "not related to the power factor of sending end",
            "less than the power factor of sending",
            "greater than the power factor of sending end"
        ],
        "answer": "less than the power factor of sending"
    }


],

    "ESAS PRE BOARDS": [

    {
        "question": "The vector which represents the sum of a group of force vector is called the ____",
        "choices": ["Magnitude", "Resultant", "Sum", "Force triangle"],
        "answer": "Resultant"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following support or connection has two unknowns?",
        "choices": ["roller support", "short linkage", "hinge support", "strut"],
        "answer": "hinge support"
    },
    {
        "question": "Definition of Strain",
        "choices": ["force per unit area", "force per unit length", "force per unit volume", "deformation per unit length"],
        "answer": "deformation per unit length"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is another term for modulus of rigidity?",
        "choices": ["Modulus of elasticity", "Young's modulus", "Bulk modulus", "Shear modulus"],
        "answer": "Shear modulus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Structural steel element subjected to torsion will develop",
        "choices": ["Tensile stress", "Shearing stress", "Compressive stress", "Bending stress"],
        "answer": "Shearing stress"
    },
    {
        "question": "A thin homogenous metallic plate containing a hole is heated sufficiently to cause expansion. If the coefficient of surface expansion is linear, the area of the hole will?",
        "choices": [
            "Increase at twice the rate as the area of the metal increases",
            "Increased at the same rate as the area of the metal",
            "Stay the same",
            "Decrease the same rate as the area of the metal decreases"
        ],
        "answer": "Increased at the same rate as the area of the metal"
    },
    {
        "question": "The deflection of a beam is ____",
        "choices": [
            "directly proportional to the modulus of elasticity and moment of inertia",
            "inversely proportional to the modulus of elasticity and length of the beam cubed",
            "inversely proportional to the modulus of elasticity and moment of inertia",
            "directly proportional to the load imposed and inversely to the length squared"
        ],
        "answer": "inversely proportional to the modulus of elasticity and moment of inertia"
    },
    {
        "question": "A leak from a faucet comes out in separate drops. Which of the following is the main cause of this phenomenon?",
        "choices": ["gravity", "air resistance", "viscosity of the liquid", "surface tension"],
        "answer": "surface tension"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT the basic component of motion of a fluid element?",
        "choices": ["translation", "rotation", "twist", "volume distortion"],
        "answer": "twist"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a fluid flows through a pipe of cross-sectional area \"A\" and a velocity \"V\", the flow or discharge is ____",
        "choices": ["AV²", "AV", "A²V", "A2/4V"],
        "answer": "AV"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the classification of a turbine if the water moves along the vanes towards the axis of rotation of the runner?",
        "choices": ["Axial flow", "Radial flow", "Parallel flow", "Mixed flow"],
        "answer": "Radial flow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is TRUE for a propeller-type impeller centrifugal pump?",
        "choices": [
            "The head developed is due to the push of the vanes and flow is almost entirely axial",
            "The head developed cannot be determined by the rotation of the vanes",
            "The head developed is due to the rotation of the impeller",
            "The head developed is due to the action of centrifugal force"
        ],
        "answer": "The head developed is due to the push of the vanes and flow is almost entirely axial"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following provides the basis for measuring thermodynamic property of temperature?",
        "choices": [
            "Zeroth law of thermodynamics",
            "First law of thermodynamics",
            "Second law of thermodynamics",
            "Third law of thermodynamics"
        ],
        "answer": "Zeroth law of thermodynamics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Modern steam plants work on which of the following cycles?",
        "choices": ["Carnot cycle", "Rankine cycle", "Otto cycle", "Bell- Coleman cycle"],
        "answer": "Rankine cycle"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following is the correct order of energy conversion in thermal power plants:",
        "choices": [
            "Chemical energy - Mechanical energy - Electrical energy",
            "Mechanical energy -Chemical energy -Electrical energy",
            "Wind energy - Mechanical energy - Electrical energy",
            "Heat energy - Electrical energy - Mechanical energy"
        ],
        "answer": "Chemical energy - Mechanical energy - Electrical energy"
    },
    {
        "question": "An adiabatic process is characterized by which of the following?",
        "choices": ["it is reversible", "The heat transfer is zero", "it is isothermal", "The entropy change is zero"],
        "answer": "The heat transfer is zero"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of a superheated, closed Rankine cycle over an open Rankine cycle?",
        "choices": [
            "lower equipment costs",
            "increased efficiency",
            "increased turbine life",
            "increase boiler life"
        ],
        "answer": "increase boiler life"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cycle is generally used for gas turbine?",
        "choices": ["Otto cycle", "Dual cycle", "Rankine cycle", "Brayton cycle"],
        "answer": "Brayton cycle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about work for quasi-equilibrium process is incorrect?",
        "choices": [
            "The differential work is inexact",
            "Work is area under P-T",
            "Work is a path function",
            "Work is always zero for constant-volume"
        ],
        "answer": "Work is area under P-T"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the empirical formula for nitric acid?",
        "choices": ["HNO2", "HNO3", "NH2OH", "NH4OH"],
        "answer": "HNO3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxidation state of Aluminum?",
        "choices": ["+2", "+3", "-4", "-2"],
        "answer": "+3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What must be the condition for Ideal gas law?",
        "choices": [
            "low temperature, low pressure",
            "low temperature, high pressure",
            "high temperature, low pressure",
            "high temperature, high pressure"
        ],
        "answer": "high temperature, low pressure"
    },
    {
        "question": "Heating value of coal largely depends on ____",
        "choices": ["moisture content", "volatile matter", "size of coal particles", "ash content"],
        "answer": "ash content"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a non-renewable source of energy?",
        "choices": ["solar", "wind", "fossil fuel", "hydro"],
        "answer": "fossil fuel"
    },
    {
        "question": "The word \"atom\" came from the Greek word \"Atomos\" meaning?",
        "choices": ["Divisible", "Indivisible", "Microscopic", "Invincible"],
        "answer": "Indivisible"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the heaviest subatomic particle?",
        "choices": ["electron", "proton", "atom", "neutron"],
        "answer": "neutron"
    },
    {
        "question": "What refers to ions that are NOT involved in the overall reactions?",
        "choices": ["Guest ions", "Spectator ions", "Extra ions", "Special ions"],
        "answer": "Spectator ions"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of Manganese Sulfide in steel alloying is to increase",
        "choices": ["brittleness", "atmospheric corrosion resistance", "machinability", "dynamic & high temperature strength"],
        "answer": "machinability"
    },
    {
        "question": "What prefix in steel identification means it is made in an electric furnace?",
        "choices": ["X", "B", "H", "E"],
        "answer": "E"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following treatments will result in an increase in the fatigue strength of the steel?",
        "choices": ["Shot peening", "Surface roughening", "Cold working", "Annealing"],
        "answer": "Shot peening"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the property of material that reflects light that strikes to its surface, making it to look shiny?",
        "choices": ["ductility", "malleability", "luster", "plasticity"],
        "answer": "luster"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following describes the meaning of spectroscopy?",
        "choices": [
            "Study of the interaction between matter and electromagnetic radiation",
            "Study of the quantitative measurement of the refiection or transmission properties",
            "Is a set of techniques for measuring electromagnetic radiation, including visible light.",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Study of the interaction between matter and electromagnetic radiation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the imperfections on electron microscope or refractive lenses?",
        "choices": ["Deformation", "Alteration", "Aberration", "Atomization"],
        "answer": "Aberration"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two's complement can be obtained from One's complement by?",
        "choices": ["adding 1", "subtracting 1", "putting 1 as leading beat", "they are equal"],
        "answer": "adding 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following bus has a function of directing memory and I/O devices?",
        "choices": ["Device bus", "Data bus", "Control bus", "Address bus"],
        "answer": "Address bus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and the like has a web level of_",
        "choices": ["4", "3", "2", "1"],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an instruction that causes data to be brought from the memory into an accumulator register?",
        "choices": ["Load", "Loop", "Fetch", "Jump"],
        "answer": "Load"
    },
    {
        "question": "A software program designed to enter a computer system, usually a network, through security \"holes\" and then replicate itself.",
        "choices": ["Computer virus", "Worm", "Trojan Horse", "HTTP"],
        "answer": "Worm"
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of outsmarting the search engine is",
        "choices": ["Google fooling", "Rank enhancement", "Search Engine Optimization", "Search Engine Hacking"],
        "answer": "Search Engine Optimization"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following computer language is used for Artificial Intelligence?",
        "choices": ["FORTRAN", "C++", "PROLOG", "COBOL"],
        "answer": "PROLOG"
    },
    {
        "question": "In MATLAB which is NOT aspect of a for/while loop?",
        "choices": ["update", "initialization", "runner", "condition"],
        "answer": "runner"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to see if two elements are equal in MATLAB?",
        "choices": ["!=", "==", "=", "isequal"],
        "answer": "=="
    },
    {
        "question": "The simplex method is extremely efficient in solving which of following classic problems?",
        "choices": ["the \"transportation problem\"", "the \"assignment problem\"", "the \"transshipment problem\"", "the \"allocation problem\""],
        "answer": "the \"allocation problem\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a full-duplex communication?",
        "choices": ["Local Area Network", "Radar", "Telemetry", "Telephone"],
        "answer": "Radar"
    },
    {
        "question": "What frequency range does cellular phone belongs?",
        "choices": ["SHF", "UHF", "VHF", "EHF"],
        "answer": "UHF"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is work in process in accountancy?",
        "choices": ["Assets", "Liabilities", "Expenses", "Revenue"],
        "answer": "Assets"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does \"NOT\" affect the owner's equity?",
        "choices": ["Invested capital", "Expenses to get license to start operation", "Dividend paid", "License to start the business"],
        "answer": "License to start the business"
    },
    {
        "question": "This provides detailed information about specific hazardous material and contains some of the following such name of substance, physical hazards, health hazards, safe handling procedures, control measures, emergency first aid procedures, etc. What is this called?",
        "choices": ["Management Safety Duty Sheet", "Material Signages Data Sheet", "Management Safety Data Sheet", "Material Safety Data Sheet"],
        "answer": "Material Safety Data Sheet"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are appointed as a division manager, which of the following task is MOST likely you will do?",
        "choices": ["determine the resources needed", "develop strategies and tactics", "set a standard", "set goals"],
        "answer": "set goals"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is material usage variance defined?",
        "choices": [
            "(quantity purchased)(actual price)-(quantity purchased) (standard price)",
            "(quantity issued - standard quantity)(standard price)",
            "(actual price - standard price)(quantity used)",
            "(quantity purchased-quantity used)(actual price)"
        ],
        "answer": "(quantity issued - standard quantity)(standard price)"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is a critical function in any service industry. It involves planning, coordinating, and controlling the resources and processes required to meet customer demand.",
        "choices": [
            "Supervisor Operation Management",
            "Service Operation Management",
            "Company Operation Management",
            "Technical Operation Management"
        ],
        "answer": "Service Operation Management"
    },
    {
        "question": "As an entrepreneur, you should always equip yourself with the current trend and always be aware of what's happening around you.",
        "choices": ["Risk taking", "Information seeking", "Goal setting", "Systematic planning and monitoring"],
        "answer": "Information seeking"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Registered Electrical Engineer (REE) Licensure Exam, the weight of \"Mathematics\" is?",
        "choices": ["45%", "20%", "25%", "30%"],
        "answer": "25%"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is \"commission\" in Implementing Rules and Regulations (IRR) of R.A. 7920, Article I, Rule 2(b)?",
        "choices": [
            "Professional Regulation Commission (PRC)",
            "Board of Electrical Engineer",
            "Charmain of PRC",
            "Commission of Higher Education"
        ],
        "answer": "Professional Regulation Commission (PRC)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of PRBEE?",
        "choices": [
            "Professional Regulation Board of Electrical Engineering",
            "Professional Regulating Board of Electrical Engineers",
            "Professional Regulatory Board of Electrical Engineering",
            "Profession Regulation Board of Electrical Engineers"
        ],
        "answer": "Professional Regulatory Board of Electrical Engineering"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approved date of PEC Part 1, 2017 edition?",
        "choices": ["November 31,2017", "December 2,2017", "January 1, 2018", "January 2,2018"],
        "answer": "December 2,2017"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum ampacity of feeders for motor and other load connected?",
        "choices": [
            "250% of full load current plus other load",
            "125% of full load current plus other load",
            "125% of full load current",
            "250% of full load current"
        ],
        "answer": "125% of full load current plus other load"
    },
    {
        "question": "In house wiring, ground conductors must NOT be",
        "choices": ["Insulated", "Identified", "placed in a circuit", "fused"],
        "answer": "fused"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fluorescent luminaires CANNOT be directly mounted to due to possibility of fluorescent luminaires of causing fire.",
        "choices": ["Concrete ceiling", "Plasters", "Plywood ceiling", "Wooden framing members"],
        "answer": "Plywood ceiling"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times the diameter of the largest raceways shall the length of the box be in straight pulls?",
        "choices": ["6", "5", "8", "10"],
        "answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best defined the phrase \"likely to become energized\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Failure of insulation",
            "High-voltage equipment",
            "Near energized electrical equipment",
            "Equipment that is exposed to lightning"
        ],
        "answer": "Failure of insulation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is also referred to as the \"Energy Efficiency Conservation Act\"?",
        "choices": ["R.A.9136", "R.A.11285", "R.A.11361", "R.A.9513"],
        "answer": "R.A.11285"
    },
    {
        "question": "The electric power industry was divided into four sectors by R.A. 9136 namely: generation, transmission, distribution, and_",
        "choices": ["Electricity end-users", "Commercial consumers", "supply", "residential consumers"],
        "answer": "supply"
    },
    {
        "question": "It refers to the process of increasing the electrical properties and/or characteristic of the power line and its associated facilities to accommodate the present and future requirements of the system or of the grid.",
        "choices": ["Upgrading", "Uprating", "Updating", "Renovating"],
        "answer": "Uprating"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Power Line Corridor (PLC) shall be determined by _ in accordance with the PEC, and to be approved by",
        "choices": ["BEE, DOE", "ERC committee, PEE", "PEE, ERC committee", "DOE, BEE"],
        "answer": "BEE, DOE"
    }

],
	
};



let questionPool = [];
let currentQuestionIndex = 0;

const menuContainer = document.getElementById("menu-container");
const quizContainer = document.getElementById("quiz-container");
const categoryTitle = document.getElementById("category-title");
const questionElement = document.getElementById("question");
const choicesContainer = document.getElementById("choices-container");
const nextButton = document.getElementById("next-button");
const restartButton = document.getElementById("restart-button");

document.querySelectorAll(".category").forEach(button => {
    button.addEventListener("click", () => {
        const selectedCategory = button.getAttribute("data-category");
        startQuiz(selectedCategory);
    });
});

function startQuiz(category) {
    questionPool = [...categories[category]];
    questionPool = shuffleArray(questionPool);
    currentQuestionIndex = 0;

    categoryTitle.textContent = category;
    menuContainer.style.display = "none";
    quizContainer.style.display = "block";

    /* ✅ **Added Fade-in Effect for the Quiz Section** ✅ */
    quizContainer.style.opacity = "0";
    setTimeout(() => { quizContainer.style.opacity = "1"; }, 100);

    loadQuestion();
}

function shuffleArray(array) {
    for (let i = array.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
        const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
        [array[i], array[j]] = [array[j], array[i]]; // Swap elements
    }
    return array;
}

function loadQuestion() {
    if (questionPool.length === 0) {
        questionElement.textContent = "🎉 REFRESH MO LANG PARA MAULIT MAY BUG KASI YUNG RESTART BUTTON HAHA 🎉";
        choicesContainer.innerHTML = "";
        nextButton.style.display = "none";
        restartButton.style.display = "inline-block";

     
        quizContainer.classList.add("celebrate");
        setTimeout(() => quizContainer.classList.remove("celebrate"), 2000);

        return;
    }

    const currentQuestion = questionPool[currentQuestionIndex];
    questionElement.textContent = currentQuestion.question;
    choicesContainer.innerHTML = "";

    currentQuestion.choices.forEach(choice => {
        const button = document.createElement("button");
        button.textContent = choice;
        button.classList.add("choice");
        button.addEventListener("click", () => handleChoice(button, choice, currentQuestion.answer));

        /* ✅ **Smooth Button Click Effect** ✅ */
        button.style.transition = "transform 0.2s ease";
        button.addEventListener("mousedown", () => button.style.transform = "scale(0.95)");
        button.addEventListener("mouseup", () => button.style.transform = "scale(1)");

        choicesContainer.appendChild(button);
    });

    nextButton.disabled = true;
}

const wrongSound = new Audio('wrong1.mp3'); // Ensure "wrong.mp3" is in your project folder

function handleChoice(button, selected, correct) {
    const buttons = document.querySelectorAll(".choice");
    buttons.forEach(btn => {
        btn.disabled = true;
        if (btn.textContent === correct) {
            btn.classList.add("correct");
		btn.style.boxShadow = "0 0 10px #28a745";
        } else if (btn.textContent === selected) {
            btn.classList.add("incorrect");
		btn.style.animation = "shake 0.3s ease-in-out";
            wrongSound.play(); // Play sound when answer is incorrect
        }
    });

    if (selected === correct) {
        questionPool.splice(currentQuestionIndex, 1); // Remove question if answered correctly
    } else {
        questionPool.push(questionPool[currentQuestionIndex]); // Add question back to the pool if answered incorrectly
        questionPool.splice(currentQuestionIndex, 1); // Remove current question from this round
    }

    nextButton.disabled = false;
}

nextButton.addEventListener("click", () => {
    /* ✅ **Added Smooth Transition Between Questions** ✅ */
    quizContainer.style.opacity = "0";
    setTimeout(() => {
        loadQuestion();
        quizContainer.style.opacity = "1";
    }, 300);
});

restartButton.addEventListener("click", () => {
    // ✅ Reset Everything Like a Fresh App Start
    menuContainer.style.display = "block"; // Show menu again
    quizContainer.style.display = "none"; // Hide quiz
    quizContainer.classList.remove("celebrate");

    // ✅ Reset Buttons and UI
    nextButton.style.display = "none";  // Hide Next button initially
    restartButton.style.display = "none";  // Hide Restart button

    // ✅ Reload Question Pool to Start Fresh
    questionPool = []; // Clear old questions
    currentQuestionIndex = 0; // Reset index

    // ✅ Reload Category Selection to Restart Properly
    document.querySelectorAll(".category").forEach(button => {
        button.addEventListener("click", () => {
            const selectedCategory = button.getAttribute("data-category");
            startQuiz(selectedCategory);
        });
    });
});
